<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ed Reform on @alspur</title>
    <link>/tags/ed-reform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ed Reform on @alspur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ed-reform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Success in Education</title>
      <link>/measuring-success-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/measuring-success-in-education/</guid>
      <description>Do low-stakes international assessments of student performance accurately describe student ability? According to this recent NBER Working paper, a country&amp;rsquo;s results may depend on their students&amp;rsquo; intrinsic motivation to do well.
The authors used an experimental approach that offered treatment students a small financial incentive to do well on a test. Students in the treatment group were told just before the test that an envelope with the equivalent of $25 (US) was theirs, but that $1 would be subtracted for each incorrect answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Why Knowledge Matters</title>
      <link>/book-notes---why-knowledge-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 06:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/book-notes---why-knowledge-matters/</guid>
      <description>E.D. Hirsch is a self-described &amp;ldquo;hedgehog,&amp;rdquo; viewing the world through the lens of one big idea:
 &amp;ldquo;[T]he achievement gap is chiefly a knowledge gap and a language gap. It can be greatly ameliorated by knowledge-based schooling.&amp;rdquo;
 The inverse of Hirsch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;big idea&amp;rdquo; is the skills-based approach to education that drives instruction in the vast majority of American schools. The Schools We Need &amp;amp; Why We Don&amp;rsquo;t Have Them&amp;rdquo; was my first introduction to the &amp;ldquo;knowledge vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Turned Upside Down</title>
      <link>/the-world-turned-upside-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 05:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-world-turned-upside-down/</guid>
      <description>After 11 years of litigation, Judge Thomas Moukawsher issued a seismic decision in the CCJEF school finance lawsuit. In the decision, Moukawsher not only eviscerated Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s school finance system, he also detailed flaws in the state&amp;rsquo;s approach to teacher evaluation, teacher compensation, the lack of clear definitions of success in elementary and secondary education, and gave the state 180 days to come up with a solution to all of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Orientation and Educational Performance</title>
      <link>/long-term-orientation-and-educational-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 08:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/long-term-orientation-and-educational-performance/</guid>
      <description>If there&amp;rsquo;s one common thread between Robin Lake relating The Boys in the Boat to schools, Neerav Kingsland on a recent charter study, and Robert Pondiscio on Hillbilly Elegy, it&amp;rsquo;s that culture plays a huge role in education. A new NBER Working Paper provides powerful evidence that it may be even more critical than was previously understood.
The authors examine the performance of first and second generation immigrant students in Florida to understand the relationship between the &amp;ldquo;long-term orientation&amp;rdquo; of the cultures they come from to their educational outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregation Theory and Education</title>
      <link>/aggregation-theory-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 06:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aggregation-theory-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Five years ago, Marc Andressen took to the pages of the Wall Street Journal to describe how software was &amp;ldquo;eating the world&amp;rdquo;:
 &amp;ldquo;More and more major businesses and industries are being run on software and delivered as online services—from movies to agriculture to national defense. Many of the winners are Silicon Valley-style entrepreneurial technology companies that are invading and overturning established industry structures. Over the next 10 years, I expect many more industries to be disrupted by software, with new world-beating Silicon Valley companies doing the disruption in more cases than not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectuals are Freaks</title>
      <link>/intellectuals-are-freaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intellectuals-are-freaks/</guid>
      <description>Michael Lind on the weakness of intellectuals&amp;rsquo; approach to inequality:
 The views of intellectuals about social reform tend to be warped by professional and personal biases, as well. In the U.S. the default prescription for inequality and other social problems among professors, pundits, and policy wonks alike tends to be: More education! Successful intellectuals get where they are by being good at taking tests and by going to good schools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The objective paradox</title>
      <link>/the-objective-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-objective-paradox/</guid>
      <description>This entire article on creativity is worth a read, but one passage in particular caught my attention:
 In one experiment a bipedal robot programmed to walk farther and farther actually ended up walking less far than one that simply was programmed to do something novel again and again, Stanley writes. Falling on the ground and flailing your legs doesn’t look much like walking, but it’s a good way to learn to oscillate, and oscillation is the most effective motion for walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Conceit &amp; ESSA</title>
      <link>/the-fatal-conceit--essa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-fatal-conceit--essa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The curious task of economics is to demonstrate to men how little they really know about what they imagine they can design&amp;rdquo; - F.A. Hayek, The Fatal Conceit
 The ink on the recently released Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) is barely dry, but progressive ed reformers are already panning the proposed successor to the defunct No Child Left Behind Act (NCLB). Conor Williams argues that not only should Obama veto the NCLB rewrite, progressives should fear it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>