<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on @alspur</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on @alspur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 08:21:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Management Quality in Public Education</title>
      <link>/management-quality-in-public-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 08:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/management-quality-in-public-education/</guid>
      <description>What impact does a high-quality superintendent have on student performance? A new NBER paper by Victor Lavy and Adi Boiko investigates this question using data from schools in Israel, finding a significant effect on student achievement (.04 SD) for top-quality superintendents. From the abstract:
 We exploit a quasi-random matching of superintendent and schools, and estimate that superintendent value added has positive and significant effects on primary and middle school students’ test scores in math, Hebrew, and English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Success in Education</title>
      <link>/measuring-success-in-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/measuring-success-in-education/</guid>
      <description>Do low-stakes international assessments of student performance accurately describe student ability? According to this recent NBER Working paper, a country&amp;rsquo;s results may depend on their students&amp;rsquo; intrinsic motivation to do well.
The authors used an experimental approach that offered treatment students a small financial incentive to do well on a test. Students in the treatment group were told just before the test that an envelope with the equivalent of $25 (US) was theirs, but that $1 would be subtracted for each incorrect answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving beyond a craft</title>
      <link>/moving-beyond-a-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 09:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/moving-beyond-a-craft/</guid>
      <description>Tyler Cowen recently interviewed Atul Gawande on his podcast, Conversations with Tyler. It’s a great episode and worth listening to the whole thing, but one section in particular stood out to me. From the transcript:
 COWEN: What’s the number one thing missing in medical education today, for doctors?
GAWANDE: I think the number one thing is an education around the fact that we are no longer a craft. It’s no longer an individual craft of being the smartest, most experienced, and capable individual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How long is your project?</title>
      <link>/how-long-is-your-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-long-is-your-project/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago, we sold our house in Branford - a beautiful shoreline town just east of New Haven - and moved to Kentucky. Of all the things that we could miss about our life in Connecticut, like lobster rolls or getting Patriots games on broadcast channels, what we miss most is the tight-knit community in Branford. We couldn’t go to the grocery store or get an ice cream cone without chatting with a neighbor, a family from a lacrosse team I coached, or someone from our gym.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidytext analysis of podcast transcripts</title>
      <link>/tidytext-analysis-of-podcast-transcripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 18:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tidytext-analysis-of-podcast-transcripts/</guid>
      <description>I listen to podcasts for several hours each day. When I wake up, I launch Overcast and listen to a podcast while I have coffee. They&amp;rsquo;re playing my drive to work, sometimes while I work,1 and when I&amp;rsquo;m running my shutdown routine at night to get ready for the next day.
I love my podcasts.
Earlier this year, _DavidSmith released a side project, Podcast Search. His description of this project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the analysts with tidytext</title>
      <link>/analyzing-the-analysts-with-tidytext/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/analyzing-the-analysts-with-tidytext/</guid>
      <description>The publication of a Capstone Report is the culmination of the Strategic Data Project&amp;rsquo;s Fellowship. These reports highlight the impact Fellows have on their respective education agencies. There are more than thirty Capstone reports on the SDP website, sorted into four broad categories:
 Data Capacity, Quality, &amp;amp; Culture Teacher Effectiveness Post-secondary Access &amp;amp; Success School Improvement &amp;amp; Redesign  This gives us a general idea of the topics Fellows were covering in their reports, but it would be nice to get a little more detail without having to read more than two dozen reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDP Convening 2017</title>
      <link>/sdp-convening-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 22:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sdp-convening-2017/</guid>
      <description>This was my second year attending the Strategic Data Project (SDP) Convening, the annual gathering of SDP Fellows and other education data nerds. There’s a ton of great content and conversation during the three days of Convening, here are some of the highlights from my perspective:
 Rick Hess kicked off the 2017 Convening with a brief talk on his latest book, Letters to a Young Education Reformer. His writing has been a big influence on my thinking when it comes to education policy, so it was pretty great hearing him speak in person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School choice via U-Haul</title>
      <link>/school-choice-via-u-haul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 13:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/school-choice-via-u-haul/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week, Alex Hernandez argued that 43 percent of children in the United States are benefiting from school choice. In The 74, he wrote:
 School districts assign children to public schools based on where they live. Then, the world’s largest game of musical chairs begins. The families of 24 million students find ways around their forced assignments to get the schools they want for their kids.
The biggest school choice group is families who move to a new neighborhood to change their assigned school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Is Counting on Its Bet on Watson</title>
      <link>/ibm-is-counting-on-its-bet-on-watson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ibm-is-counting-on-its-bet-on-watson/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, Watson isn&amp;rsquo;t just playing Jeopardy:
 At the University of North Carolina School of Medicine, Watson was tested on 1,000 cancer diagnoses made by human experts. In 99 percent of them, Watson recommended the same treatment as the oncologists.
In 30 percent of the cases, Watson also found a treatment option the human doctors missed. Some treatments were based on research papers that the doctors had not read — more than 160,000 cancer research papers are published a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Why Knowledge Matters</title>
      <link>/book-notes---why-knowledge-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 06:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/book-notes---why-knowledge-matters/</guid>
      <description>E.D. Hirsch is a self-described &amp;ldquo;hedgehog,&amp;rdquo; viewing the world through the lens of one big idea:
 &amp;ldquo;[T]he achievement gap is chiefly a knowledge gap and a language gap. It can be greatly ameliorated by knowledge-based schooling.&amp;rdquo;
 The inverse of Hirsch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;big idea&amp;rdquo; is the skills-based approach to education that drives instruction in the vast majority of American schools. The Schools We Need &amp;amp; Why We Don&amp;rsquo;t Have Them&amp;rdquo; was my first introduction to the &amp;ldquo;knowledge vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blame the Elites for the Trump Phenomenon</title>
      <link>/blame-the-elites-for-the-trump-phenomenon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blame-the-elites-for-the-trump-phenomenon/</guid>
      <description>Intelligence Squared hosts Oxford-style debates, with two teams supporting or opposing a motion. The motion of their most recent debate: blame the elites for the Trump phenomenon.
Personally, I&amp;rsquo;m for the motion, but I would encourage you to watch and decide for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Turned Upside Down</title>
      <link>/the-world-turned-upside-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 05:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-world-turned-upside-down/</guid>
      <description>After 11 years of litigation, Judge Thomas Moukawsher issued a seismic decision in the CCJEF school finance lawsuit. In the decision, Moukawsher not only eviscerated Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s school finance system, he also detailed flaws in the state&amp;rsquo;s approach to teacher evaluation, teacher compensation, the lack of clear definitions of success in elementary and secondary education, and gave the state 180 days to come up with a solution to all of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a free distributed data collection &#34;app&#34; with R and Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/how-to-create-a-free-distributed-data-collection-app-with-r-and-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 06:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-create-a-free-distributed-data-collection-app-with-r-and-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>A really neat concept that reminds me of my time tracking method:
 Jenny Bryan, developer of the google sheets R package, gave a talk at Use2015 about the package.
One of the things that got me most excited about the package was an example she gave in her talk of using the Google Sheets package for data collection at ultimate frisbee tournaments. One reason is that I used to play a little ultimate back in the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Orientation and Educational Performance</title>
      <link>/long-term-orientation-and-educational-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 08:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/long-term-orientation-and-educational-performance/</guid>
      <description>If there&amp;rsquo;s one common thread between Robin Lake relating The Boys in the Boat to schools, Neerav Kingsland on a recent charter study, and Robert Pondiscio on Hillbilly Elegy, it&amp;rsquo;s that culture plays a huge role in education. A new NBER Working Paper provides powerful evidence that it may be even more critical than was previously understood.
The authors examine the performance of first and second generation immigrant students in Florida to understand the relationship between the &amp;ldquo;long-term orientation&amp;rdquo; of the cultures they come from to their educational outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESSA and the Administrative State</title>
      <link>/essa-and-the-administrative-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 06:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/essa-and-the-administrative-state/</guid>
      <description>Chad Aldeman on the delegation of policy making in ESSA:
 Congress was able to reach broad bipartisan agreement on ESSA mainly because it punted on a number of key policy questions. Any reading of ESSA leaves one wondering what exactly Congress meant when it asked states to “meaningfully differentiate” among schools, when it required that states give “substantial weight” to each indicator, or when it stipulated that academic indicators count for “much greater weight” than non-academic ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregation Theory and Education</title>
      <link>/aggregation-theory-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 06:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aggregation-theory-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Five years ago, Marc Andressen took to the pages of the Wall Street Journal to describe how software was &amp;ldquo;eating the world&amp;rdquo;:
 &amp;ldquo;More and more major businesses and industries are being run on software and delivered as online services—from movies to agriculture to national defense. Many of the winners are Silicon Valley-style entrepreneurial technology companies that are invading and overturning established industry structures. Over the next 10 years, I expect many more industries to be disrupted by software, with new world-beating Silicon Valley companies doing the disruption in more cases than not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why American Schools Are Even More Unequal Than We Thought</title>
      <link>/why-american-schools-are-even-more-unequal-than-we-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 14:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-american-schools-are-even-more-unequal-than-we-thought/</guid>
      <description>Using data to inform our conversations about public school performance is a good idea, but too often, the measures we use are reduced to imprecise terms like &amp;ldquo;proficiency,&amp;rdquo; which can carry several different meanings when describing a local, state, or national assessment1.
As Susan Dynarski notes in The Upshot, this is also a common problem with the most-frequently used proxy for &amp;ldquo;poverty&amp;rdquo; in education, Free/Reduced Price Lunch (FRPL) eligibility:
 &amp;ldquo;Nearly half of students nationwide are eligible for a subsidized meal in school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - The Checklist Manifesto</title>
      <link>/book-notes---the-checklist-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 06:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/book-notes---the-checklist-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>Books have always been important to me. My grandmother was a librarian and as she babysat me, I was able to spend hundreds, if not thousands, of hours searching, consuming, and falling in love with books. That passion continues today, but I find that I have less time to devote to extended, deep periods of reading.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to follow CGP Grey&amp;rsquo;s lead and start publicly sharing notes on books I&amp;rsquo;ve read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tinkering</title>
      <link>/tinkering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 09:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tinkering/</guid>
      <description>The most recent episode of Mad Dogs &amp;amp; Englishmen1 starts off with a discussion of buying and assembling and AR-15 from scratch. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting process, but the conversation took an even more interesting turn as they focused on the decline of a tinkering ethos in our society.
The machines and devices we use are often too complex to repair, disassemble, or customize. If you open the hood of your car, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see or even access many of the most critical parts - you&amp;rsquo;ll most likely see a series of injection-molded plastic meant to not only protect but to discourage amateur tinkering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectuals are Freaks</title>
      <link>/intellectuals-are-freaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/intellectuals-are-freaks/</guid>
      <description>Michael Lind on the weakness of intellectuals&amp;rsquo; approach to inequality:
 The views of intellectuals about social reform tend to be warped by professional and personal biases, as well. In the U.S. the default prescription for inequality and other social problems among professors, pundits, and policy wonks alike tends to be: More education! Successful intellectuals get where they are by being good at taking tests and by going to good schools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Tracking</title>
      <link>/time-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 20:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/time-tracking/</guid>
      <description>I tweeted this out earlier today:
Insights from time tracking: I need to do more #rstats programming on Thursday/Friday afternoons. Also, mtgs suck. pic.twitter.com/14dFtGNubP
&amp;mdash; Alex Spurrier (@alspur) July 29, 2016 
Why do I have time tracking charts that break down when I do certain kinds of work?
A book (Deep Work) and a podcast (Cortex).
I know that the ability to focus is important to the work I do, but Deep Work by Cal Newport helped articulate precisely why it&amp;rsquo;s extremely important to cultivate the ability to perform &amp;ldquo;deep work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ezra Klein interviews Yuval Levin</title>
      <link>/ezra-klein-interviews-yuval-levin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 21:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/ezra-klein-interviews-yuval-levin/</guid>
      <description>This is a thoughtful, in-depth conversation that covers from the thesis of Levin&amp;rsquo;s latest book, The Fractured Republic, his experience working in the Bush (43) Administration, the most interesting policy ideas on each side of the political spectrum, and more.
This is the first Ezra Klein Show episode I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to - I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to adding others to my Overcast queue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The objective paradox</title>
      <link>/the-objective-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-objective-paradox/</guid>
      <description>This entire article on creativity is worth a read, but one passage in particular caught my attention:
 In one experiment a bipedal robot programmed to walk farther and farther actually ended up walking less far than one that simply was programmed to do something novel again and again, Stanley writes. Falling on the ground and flailing your legs doesn’t look much like walking, but it’s a good way to learn to oscillate, and oscillation is the most effective motion for walking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Conceit &amp; ESSA</title>
      <link>/the-fatal-conceit--essa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-fatal-conceit--essa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The curious task of economics is to demonstrate to men how little they really know about what they imagine they can design&amp;rdquo; - F.A. Hayek, The Fatal Conceit
 The ink on the recently released Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) is barely dry, but progressive ed reformers are already panning the proposed successor to the defunct No Child Left Behind Act (NCLB). Conor Williams argues that not only should Obama veto the NCLB rewrite, progressives should fear it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How would great teachers spend a time bonus?</title>
      <link>/how-would-great-teachers-spend-a-time-bonus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 11:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-would-great-teachers-spend-a-time-bonus/</guid>
      <description>This entire series of conversations with Fishman Prize winners is worth reading, but this passage stood out to me:
 “In so many ways, these hierarchies we have put teachers at the bottom. But that almost entitles everyone who is above us, so to speak, to put tasks on our plate.”
 It perfectly captures my feelings after reading The Allure of Order and Team of Teams: our highly bureaucratized school system is limiting the potential of our students and our educators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Obama Education Legacy</title>
      <link>/the-real-obama-education-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 08:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-real-obama-education-legacy/</guid>
      <description>Rick Hess summarizes the frustrations of center-right ed reformers with the Obama administration&amp;rsquo;s approach to education policy (myself included):
 “Although some of Obama’s education moves have been inopportune, his agenda has also included a number of notions with real promise. But his administration’s excessive faith in federal regulation, lack of time for the niceties of federalism, and contempt for critics helped undermine these ideas and support for reform more broadly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Taylorism, Part III</title>
      <link>/beyond-taylorism-part-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/beyond-taylorism-part-iii/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you&amp;rsquo;ve read articles, essays, and books that attempt to explain the root cause of the problems facing the teaching profession. In The Allure of Order, Jal Mehta only needs one paragraph to break it down: &amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;In the longer term, the success of the reformers in the Progressive Era resulted in a shift from one-room schoolhouses to urban school systems, in which schools were expected to follow the directives of a central manager in a district office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Taylorism, Part II</title>
      <link>/beyond-taylorism-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/beyond-taylorism-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>When we realized __________, we did what most large organizations do when they find themselves falling behind the competition: we worked harder. We deployed more resources, we put more people to work, and we strove to create ever-greater efficiency within the existing operating model. Like obnoxious tourists trying to make themselves understood in a foreign country by continuing to speak their native tongue louder and louder we were raising the volume to no good end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Taylorism, Part I</title>
      <link>/beyond-taylorism-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/beyond-taylorism-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Three books on three seemingly different topics changed how I think about public policy.
My reading list this month came together serendipitously. A tweet led me to buy The Conservative Heart, I ordered Team of Teams after listening to a podcast, and purchased The Allure of Order after reading Neerav Kingsland&amp;rsquo;s blogs about it.
At a first glance, these books don&amp;rsquo;t look like they&amp;rsquo;d fit together. The Conservative Heart is about communicating a conservative anti-poverty agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deal on charters in detail</title>
      <link>/deal-on-charters-in-detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deal-on-charters-in-detail/</guid>
      <description>The CT Mirror reports that Governor Malloy and Democratic legislators struck a budget deal that would allow two new charter schools to open as well as supporting the growth of existing charter schools.1
On paper, this charter growth will cost the state $12.4 million in FY16, but it actually took an additional $23.5 million increase in FY16 ECS funding to make it happen. In other words, for every $1 in new funding to support growth in charter schools, legislators insisted that $2 went to support traditional public schools via ECS grants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Choices</title>
      <link>/hard-choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hard-choices/</guid>
      <description>There are few people in Connecticut defending the current system of distributing Education Cost Sharing (ECS) grants. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s a formula that is supposed to guide annual appropriations, but there are two big problems. To start, the legislature hasn&amp;rsquo;t ever appropriated the level of funding the formula calls for. Given the economic tumult of the past decade and Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s somewhat anemic growth rate, it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to understand why this is the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More data please</title>
      <link>/more-data-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/more-data-please/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago, Rob Stellar wrote about the low rate of college completion among Hartford Public School graduates on TrendCT. More importantly, he raised some important questions that may better explain what&amp;rsquo;s going on here:
 &amp;ldquo;What is preventing so many students who graduate high school from enrolling in college? Is it for financial reasons or lack of access to other resources/college prep programs? How well do Hartford high schools prepare students for college?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis on the go</title>
      <link>/data-analysis-on-the-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/data-analysis-on-the-go/</guid>
      <description>A recent Fast Company article describes Tableau&amp;rsquo;s latest app, Project Elastic, as a potential game-changer in mobile data analysis. The app would allow iPad users to move from an Excel file in Mail.app to an interactive chart with a few quick taps. Filters can be applied/removed with swipes, zoom levels are adjusted by pinch/spread gestures, and charts can be shared via email.
It&amp;rsquo;s a cleverly designed interface, but Elastic suffers from a critical problem: it assumes the user is accessing clean datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdated funding systems are limiting options for families in Connecticut.</title>
      <link>/outdated-funding-systems-are-limiting-options-for-families-in-connecticut./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/outdated-funding-systems-are-limiting-options-for-families-in-connecticut./</guid>
      <description>The Growth of School Choice in Connecticut, 1995-2015 For years, families in Connecticut demanded more public school options for their children. Over the last two decades, state funding for magnet and charter schools grew significantly.
Even with this level of growth, thousands still end up unable to attend magnet schools or charter schools due to limited capacity. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it seem reasonable that lawmakers would work to expand the number of public school options available to families?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Thought Experiment</title>
      <link>/a-thought-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-thought-experiment/</guid>
      <description>What would happen if we actually followed the ECS formula?
There are two significant flaws in Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s current school funding formula, known as ECS (Education Cost Sharing):
 It does not reflect the actual needs of towns and students. It does not treat the thousands of students accessing school choice equitably.  I plan on addressing those concerns in subsequent posts, but for a moment, let&amp;rsquo;s take ECS at face value and assume that the underpinnings of the formula are correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the problem with school finance in Connecticut?</title>
      <link>/whats-the-problem-with-school-finance-in-connecticut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/whats-the-problem-with-school-finance-in-connecticut/</guid>
      <description>School finance in Connecticut is broken.
The state&amp;rsquo;s main vehicle of support to public schools, the Education Cost Sharing (ECS) grant, sends $2 billion to local districts each year with the goal of equalizing the ability of communities to fund public education. Unfortunately, years of legislative tinkering with the ECS formula left Connecticut with a Byzantine approach to funding schools that takes more than 16 pages to explain.
On top of this labyrinthine system, non-traditional public schools (including magnet, charter, vocational/technical, and agriscience schools) are funded under entirely separate mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>