<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on @alspur</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on @alspur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 08:21:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Management Quality in Public Education</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-11-20-mgmt-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 08:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-11-20-mgmt-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What impact does a high-quality superintendent have on student performance? A new NBER paper by Victor Lavy and Adi Boiko investigates this question using data from schools in Israel, finding a significant effect on student achievement (.04 SD) for top-quality superintendents. From the abstract:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We exploit a quasi-random matching of superintendent and schools, and estimate that superintendent value added has positive and significant effects on primary and middle school students’ test scores in math, Hebrew, and English. One standard deviation improvement in superintendent value added increases test scores by about 0.04 of a standard deviation in the test score distribution. The effect doesn’t vary with students’ socio-economic background, is highly non-linear, increases sharply for superintendents in the highest-quartile of the value added distribution, and is larger for female superintendents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did top-quality superintendents achieve these results? By improving the focus and clarity of school priorities and procedures, with an emphasis on improving school climate. The authors note the similarity of this management approach to &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.harvard.edu/files/fryer/files/2014_injecting_charter_school_best_practices_into_traditional_public_schools.pdf&#34;&gt;Fryer&amp;rsquo;s 2014 study of Houston schools adopting a charter-style &amp;ldquo;no excuses&amp;rdquo; approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of this study, along with Fryer&amp;rsquo;s 2014 study, should inform the training and practice of superintendents in the United States. While successful superintendents will also likely need to develop and demonstrate competency in instructional leadership, finance, HR, and legal matters, the value-add of strength in these domains isn&amp;rsquo;t as clear. Superintendents have the most impact on student outcomes when they help bring focus and clarity to schools while also emphasizing strong school culture. The leaders and programs that embrace this approach are likely to deliver better outcomes for their students in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Success in Education</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-11-14-measuring-success-in-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-11-14-measuring-success-in-ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do low-stakes international assessments of student performance accurately describe student ability? According to this recent NBER Working paper, a country&amp;rsquo;s results may depend on their students&amp;rsquo; intrinsic motivation to do well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors used an experimental approach that offered treatment students a small financial incentive to do well on a test. Students in the treatment group were told just before the test that an envelope with the equivalent of $25 (US) was theirs, but that $1 would be subtracted for each incorrect answer. The researchers conducted the experiment in three high schools in China and two in the US. They found no impact of the financial incentive in China, but the effect size in the US was 0.20-0.23 standard deviations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors conclude that the massive difference in treatment effect between countries indicates that &amp;ldquo;success on low states assessments does not solely reflect differences in ability between students across countries&amp;rdquo; and that &amp;ldquo;low-stakes tests do not measure and compare ability in isolation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, researchers, policymakers, and the public should be a little more cautious when interpreting the results of low-stakes assessments like PISA. Student motivation clearly plays a significant role in the results of a country&amp;rsquo;s performance - a topic that deserves further investigation. For example, NCES will release new &lt;a href=&#34;https://nces.ed.gov/nationsreportcard/&#34;&gt;NAEP results&lt;/a&gt; in early 2018. Does student motivation vary significantly for NAEP across state lines? If so, how much of a role (if any) is it contributing to state performance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-stakes assessments can be informative, but they may be measuring more than student ability. This study is a reminder to policymakers and advocates to exercise caution when comparing performance on these tests across jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving beyond a craft</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-27-moving-beyond-a-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 09:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-27-moving-beyond-a-craft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://marginalrevolution.com/&#34;&gt;Tyler Cowen&lt;/a&gt; recently interviewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Atul_Gawande&#34;&gt;Atul Gawande&lt;/a&gt; on his podcast, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mercatus.org/commentary/conversations-tyler&#34;&gt;Conversations with Tyler&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a great episode and worth listening to the whole thing, but one section in particular stood out to me. From the &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/conversations-with-tyler/atul-gawande-checklist-books-tyler-cowen-d8268b8dfe53&#34;&gt;transcript&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;COWEN: What’s the number one thing missing in medical education today, for doctors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GAWANDE: I think the number one thing is an education around the fact that we are no longer a craft. It’s no longer an individual craft of being the smartest, most experienced, and capable individual. It’s a profession that has exceeded the capabilities of any individual to manage the volume of knowledge and skill required. So we are now delivering as groups of people. And knowing how to be an effective group, how to solve problems when your group is not being effective, and to enable that capability—that, I think, is not being taught, it’s not being researched. It is the biggest opportunity to advance human health, and we’re not delivering on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having worked in the education sector for a decade, it’s hard to listen to that and not consider replacing “medical education” with “educator preparation” and “human health” with “student outcomes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaching is certainly a craft that requires significant training, practice, and experience to master, but it also requires a high degree of collaboration with other teachers, administrators, support staff, parents, and students. Similar to medicine, it’s an under-taught, under-researched aspect of the profession.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How long is your project?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-07-10-how-long-is-your-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 15:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-07-10-how-long-is-your-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, we sold our house in Branford - a beautiful shoreline town just east of New Haven - and moved to Kentucky. Of all the things that we could miss about our life in Connecticut, like lobster rolls or getting Patriots games on broadcast channels, what we miss most is the tight-knit community in Branford. We couldn’t go to the grocery store or get an ice cream cone without chatting with a neighbor, a family from a lacrosse team I coached, or someone from our gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Friday, that community experienced a tragic loss: a 10 year old boy drowned in the Branford River. We woke up to the details of this event on Saturday morning. My wife turned to me and said, “It’s Ben.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben, number two of Dave’s three sons, at only 10 years old was an impressive athlete and just a wonderful person to be around. He has the kind of smile that once you see, you can’t forget it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I briefly coached Ben in lacrosse. There were a few times my U11 team was short on players, so Ben and his older brother played up an age group so we could field a full team. Even though he was the youngest on the field, Ben played with a courage, confidence, and athleticism that made him stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than knowing Ben as an athlete, we got to know Ben’s family. His father, Dave, is a coach at the gym we attended and a handyman that helped us remodel our kitchen. As Dave was hanging drywall, Ben and his older brother played in our living room and yard. Anyone that spent a few minutes with the Callahans would walk away knowing that they are a family that exudes joy, energy, and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All weekend, the incredible pain and grief of our Branford friends dominated our Facebook feeds. Those who know the Callahans from the gym, youth sports, and Sliney Elementary shared their sorrow over this tragic loss and their support for the Callahan family during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night, the Branford Town Green lived up to its role as the heart of the community. Thousands of people showed up to celebrate Ben’s life. Thanks to the reporting of Steve at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.branfordseven.com&#34;&gt;BranfordSeven.com&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to watch a live stream of the ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FBranfordSeven%2Fvideos%2F1696802467015175%2F&amp;show_text=0&amp;width=560&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;316&#34; style=&#34;border:none;overflow:hidden&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowTransparency=&#34;true&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Branford First Selectman, the Branford Public Schools Superintendent, coaches, teachers, and friends all stood up to speak about the impact Ben had on their lives. Two young men shared what they learned from Ben:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never give up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always hug your friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They then asked the thousands in attendance to hug their neighbors. Everyone did. It was Branford at its best: loving and united.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One hour, nineteen minutes, and thirty seconds into the live stream, Ben’s father Dave stood up and spoke. He spoke for about 10 minutes - it’s worth watching all of it. He closed with the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ben was given a 10 year project. God knew that before he made the world. He knew exactly what he had for Ben to do. He knew exactly how long it was going to take and man, did he kill it - he was awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I want you guys to ask yourselves a question: how long is your project? How long is it going to take?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Ben had postponed his decision for Jesus until he was in high school, or done with college, or when he got married and had kids, then he would have missed it. So I want you guys to search your heart and look for that daily relationship. It’s not religion - it’s a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walk into eternity that Ben took on Friday was determined not by his actions, but by his decision. As much as I love him and always will, I know that God loves him more. He loves everybody here in this audience so much that he was willing to watch his son die and I’ll tell you right now, after going through it, it’s not something I would do voluntarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Ben’s earthly life lasted 10 years, 6 months, and 15 days after it started and then he continues in Heaven, that’s brilliant, that’s beautiful. But if one person here, or ten people, or a thousand people here are moved to search their hearts and establish their relationship with Jesus or truly commit to it and they join Ben in Heaven when they go, then this is truly worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much guys, I’m so blessed to have you all here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave spoke with so much love, gratitude, and clarity that it’s hard for me to fathom given the pain he’s experiencing. For me, it’s difficult to understand how he could speak so eloquently in the wake of such an emotional tragedy without God’s help. It was one of the greatest displays of strength I’ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m taking up Dave’s challenge. I’m searching my heart, and for the first time in a long time, I opened my Bible this morning and prayed. I prayed for Ben, for Dave and the Callahan family, and everyone else touched by Ben’s brief, brilliant life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing a jersey with the number 2 will always be a reminder of the joy and love Ben Callahan exuded. He did a heck of a job making an impact on his community in the 10 years, 6 months, and 15 days we got to share with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How long is your project?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to support the Callahans:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gofundme.com/ben-callahan-memorial-fund&#34;&gt;Donate via GoFundMe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mealtrain.com/trains/821v65/donate/&#34;&gt;Donate and/or sign up for meal delivery via MealTrain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidytext analysis of podcast transcripts</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-06-06-tidy-pod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 18:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-06-06-tidy-pod/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I listen to podcasts for several hours each day. When I wake up, I launch &lt;a href=&#34;http://overcast.fm&#34;&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt; and listen to a podcast while I have coffee. They&amp;rsquo;re playing my drive to work, sometimes while I work,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and when I&amp;rsquo;m running my shutdown routine at night to get ready for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love my podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, &lt;a href=&#34;http://david-smith.org/&#34;&gt;_DavidSmith&lt;/a&gt; released a side project, &lt;a href=&#34;http://podsearch.david-smith.org&#34;&gt;Podcast Search&lt;/a&gt;. His description of this project:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I take a few podcasts and run them through automated speech-to-text, which is useless for reading, but works out to be just fine for keyword searching.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really cool site - particularity since it produces searchable quasi-transcripts for a few of my favorite podcasts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://atp.fm&#34;&gt;Accidental Tech Podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://relay.fm/cortex&#34;&gt;Cortex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://5by5.tv/hypercritical&#34;&gt;Hypercritical&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/thetalkshow&#34;&gt;The Talk Show&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They aren&amp;rsquo;t perfect, but it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty cool tool, and it got me thinking: wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be cool to take that text and run it through some &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidytextmining.com&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tidytext&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; functions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by scraping the raw HTML for each episode of ATP, Cortex, Hypercritical, and The Talk Show. I then did a little data cleaning to get the text from Podcast Search into &lt;a href=&#34;http://r4ds.had.co.nz/tidy-data.html&#34;&gt;a tidy format&lt;/a&gt;. There are still a few episodes of ATP and Hypercritical processing through _DavidSmith&amp;rsquo;s speech-to-text algorithm, but there&amp;rsquo;s enough data from each podcast to do some cursory text analysis using &lt;code&gt;tidytext&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of 6 June 2017, I have about 1.1 million lines of text from these four podcasts to analyze. Once I loaded the data, it was pretty easy to parse out the words spoken in each podcast using the &lt;code&gt;unnest_tokens()&lt;/code&gt; function from &lt;code&gt;tidytext&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34;&gt;# load libraries
library(tidyverse)
library(tidytext)

# load transcript data
atp &amp;lt;- read_rds(&amp;quot;data/atp.rda&amp;quot;)
cortex &amp;lt;- read_rds(&amp;quot;data/cortex.rda&amp;quot;)
hypercritical &amp;lt;- read_rds(&amp;quot;data/hypercritical.rda&amp;quot;)
the_talk_show &amp;lt;- read_rds(&amp;quot;data/tts.rda&amp;quot;)

# join podcast data together
podcasts &amp;lt;- bind_rows(atp, cortex, hypercritical, the_talk_show)

# get count of words by podcast
podcast_words &amp;lt;- podcasts %&amp;gt;% 
  unnest_tokens(word, line) %&amp;gt;%
  anti_join(stop_words) %&amp;gt;%
  count(podcast, word) %&amp;gt;%
  ungroup()
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I wanted to use &lt;code&gt;tf-idf&lt;/code&gt; to determine which words were most important to each podcast. Not familiar with this approach? Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidytextmining.com/tfidf.html#term-frequency-in-jane-austens-novels&#34;&gt;a description from the authors of the &lt;code&gt;tidytext&lt;/code&gt; package&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of tf-idf is to find the important words for the content of each document by decreasing the weight for commonly used words and increasing the weight for words that are not used very much in a collection or corpus of documents&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calculating tf-idf attempts to find the words that are important (i.e., common) in a text, but not too common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, if one of these podcasts uses an uncommon word more than others, this approach will help identify it. Here is the code I used to do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34;&gt;# count total words per podcast
total_words &amp;lt;- podcast_words %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(podcast) %&amp;gt;%
  summarise(total = sum(n))

# join individual word count and total word count
# get tf_idf by podcast
podcast_words &amp;lt;- left_join(podcast_words, total_words) %&amp;gt;% 
  bind_tf_idf(word, podcast, n)
  
# plot top 10 tf_idf words by podcast
podcast_words %&amp;gt;%  
  group_by(podcast) %&amp;gt;% 
  top_n(10) %&amp;gt;% 
  ungroup() %&amp;gt;% 
  ggplot(aes(reorder(word, tf_idf), tf_idf, fill = podcast)) +
  geom_col(show.legend=FALSE) +
  facet_wrap(~podcast, scales = &amp;quot;free&amp;quot;) +
  coord_flip() +
  labs(x = &amp;quot;tf-idf&amp;quot;,
       title = &amp;quot;Most Important Words by Podcast&amp;quot;,
       subtitle = &amp;quot;Measured by tf-idf&amp;quot;) +
  scale_fill_manual(values = c(&amp;quot;blue4&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;grey18&amp;quot;,
                               &amp;quot;palegreen4&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;lightsteelblue4&amp;quot;))+
  theme(legend.position = &amp;quot;none&amp;quot;,
        axis.title.y = element_blank())
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/tidy_pod/master/figures/podcasts.png&#34; alt=&#34;podcast plot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty interesting plot, but there&amp;rsquo;s definitely some noise here. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that there are some words that slipped through the &lt;code&gt;stop_words&lt;/code&gt; filter (like &amp;ldquo;dont&amp;rdquo;) and some words that got mixed up during the speech-to-text process like (&amp;ldquo;fd&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of noise coming from each podcast&amp;rsquo;s ad reads. I&amp;rsquo;m sure this makes the folks at Casper, Lynda, Betterment, etc. happy, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to know a little more about the actual content of these podcasts. Let&amp;rsquo;s filter those words and plot again using this code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34;&gt;podcast_plot_clean &amp;lt;- podcast_words %&amp;gt;% 
  arrange(desc(tf_idf)) %&amp;gt;% 
  filter(word != &amp;quot;mattress&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;casper&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;betterment&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;lynda&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;5x5&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;rackspace&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;mailchimp.com&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;dont&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;tts&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;afm&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;fd&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;wealthfront&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;apron&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(word != &amp;quot;cgpgrey&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(word = factor(word, levels = rev(unique(word))))

podcast_plot_clean %&amp;gt;%  
  group_by(podcast) %&amp;gt;% 
  top_n(10) %&amp;gt;% 
  ungroup() %&amp;gt;% 
  ggplot(aes(word, tf_idf, fill = podcast)) +
  geom_col(show.legend=FALSE) +
  facet_wrap(~podcast, scales = &amp;quot;free&amp;quot;) +
  coord_flip() +
  labs(x = &amp;quot;tf-idf&amp;quot;,
       title = &amp;quot;Most Important Words by Podcast&amp;quot;,
       subtitle = &amp;quot;Measured by tf-idf&amp;quot;) +
  scale_fill_manual(values = c(&amp;quot;blue4&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;grey18&amp;quot;,
                               &amp;quot;palegreen4&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;lightsteelblue4&amp;quot;))+
  theme(legend.position = &amp;quot;none&amp;quot;,
        axis.title.y = element_blank())
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/tidy_pod/master/figures/podcasts_clean.png&#34; alt=&#34;clean podcast plot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This plot provides a much better understanding of what makes each of these podcasts unique:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ATP is clearly a very technical show. From API&amp;rsquo;s to PHP, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/caseyliss&#34;&gt;Casey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/marcoarment&#34;&gt;Marco&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/siracusa&#34;&gt;John&lt;/a&gt; spend a lot of time in the weeds of technical issues. If it were one word, &amp;ldquo;file system&amp;rdquo; (🛎) would have been on this plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cortex, a show about the working habits of &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/imyke&#34;&gt;Myke Hurley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/cgpgrey&#34;&gt;CGP Grey&lt;/a&gt;, is well-represented on this plot. Productivity topics come through clearly (coworking, &lt;a href=&#34;http://trello.com&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://todoist.com&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/23&#34;&gt;Amsterdam workcations&lt;/a&gt;), as well as their involvement in the YouTube community (Pewdiepie, vlog(s), vidcon, patreon). Grey&amp;rsquo;s frequent &amp;ldquo;mhm&amp;rdquo;-ing also came through clearly via speech-to-text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypercritical&amp;rsquo;s most important words are the most complex, a reflection of the preparation and intentionality John Siracusa brought to this show. &amp;ldquo;Rumination&amp;rdquo; is the perfect word to emerge as the most important for Hypercritical.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Talk Show&amp;rsquo;s words are too perfect. John Gruber&amp;rsquo;s son Jonas takes the top spot, followed by ⚾️ (his beloved Yankees take the 10 spot). Two of the words (Vesper and bourbon) can be represented by cocktail 🍸🥃 emoji, which I&amp;rsquo;m sure would make him proud. I&amp;rsquo;m glad &amp;ldquo;dingus&amp;rdquo; and Han Solo made the list too. &amp;ldquo;Iowa&amp;rdquo;  and &amp;ldquo;bomber&amp;rdquo; made me scratch my head, but once I looked at the transcripts, it was obvious this is how the speech-to-text interpreted how Gruber pronounces &amp;ldquo;iOS&amp;rdquo; and (Steve) &amp;ldquo;Ballmer&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a pretty fun side project and there&amp;rsquo;s still a ton of data to analyze. I&amp;rsquo;ll likely write some additional posts on this front, but until then, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alspur/tidy_pod&#34;&gt;follow this repo&lt;/a&gt; to see what I&amp;rsquo;m working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Never while I code. I can&amp;rsquo;t code and listen to vocal music.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;28 of Hypercritical&amp;rsquo;s 100 episodes are still processing through the speech-to-text algorithm, so they were unavailable for this analysis.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the analysts with tidytext</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-24-analyzing-the-analysts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-24-analyzing-the-analysts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The publication of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdp.cepr.harvard.edu/fellowship-capstone-reports&#34;&gt;Capstone Report&lt;/a&gt; is the culmination of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sdp.cepr.harvard.edu/fellowship&#34;&gt;Strategic Data Project&amp;rsquo;s Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;. These reports highlight the impact Fellows have on their respective education agencies. There are more than thirty Capstone reports on the SDP website, sorted into four broad categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Capacity, Quality, &amp;amp; Culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teacher Effectiveness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post-secondary Access &amp;amp; Success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;School Improvement &amp;amp; Redesign&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives us a general idea of the topics Fellows were covering in their reports, but it would be nice to get a little more detail without having to read more than two dozen reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;code&gt;tidytext&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to play around with the &lt;code&gt;tidytext&lt;/code&gt; R package for several months. After seeing a really fun blog post using it to &lt;a href=&#34;http://mdgbeck.netlify.com/post/tidytext-analysis-of-seinfeld/&#34;&gt;analyze Seinfeld scripts&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to try and apply the &lt;code&gt;tidytext&lt;/code&gt; tools to the SDP Capstone reports, so I read through a few chapters of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tidytextmining.com/preface.html&#34;&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/a&gt; and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-reports&#34;&gt;Getting the reports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the text of each Capstone Report wasn&amp;rsquo;t too challenging. I started by parsing the lines of the webpage that you&amp;rsquo;d use to manually download the PDFs of each capstone report, then I filtered it for all the direct links to each individual PDF. After running a simple for loop, I had all 38 PDFs on my MacBook. Here&amp;rsquo;s the code I used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34;&gt;
library(RCurl)
library(tidyverse)
library(stringr)

# download report pdf&#39;s ####

# get content of sdp capstone report webpage
sdp_url &amp;lt;- getURL(&amp;quot;https://sdp.cepr.harvard.edu/fellowship-capstone-reports&amp;quot;)
sdp_webpage &amp;lt;- readLines(tc &amp;lt;- textConnection(sdp_url)); close(tc)

# create df of webpage content
sdp_df &amp;lt;- tibble(line = 1:360, content = sdp_webpage)

# find and clean links to report pdf&#39;s
capstone_links &amp;lt;- sdp_df %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(link_present = str_detect(content, &amp;quot;https://sdp.cepr.harvard.edu/files/cepr-sdp/files/&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;%
  filter(link_present == TRUE) %&amp;gt;%
  mutate(clean_link = str_extract(content, &amp;quot;https://sdp.cepr.harvard.edu/files/cepr-sdp/files/.+\\.pdf&amp;quot;))

# download report pdfs and save them in &#39;/reports&#39;
for(i in seq_along(1:length(capstone_links$clean_link))){
  
  report_url &amp;lt;- capstone_links$clean_link[i]
  
  download.file(report_url, str_c(&amp;quot;reports/capstone&amp;quot;, i,&amp;quot;.pdf&amp;quot;))
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-the-text&#34;&gt;Getting the text&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After downloading the Capstone Reports, I needed to extract the text in each report, so I relied a function from the &lt;code&gt;pdftools&lt;/code&gt; package. My code could probably be more efficient and there were some font-related errors, but I was able to extract the text from each report as a series of bigrams and then plot the result. Again, here&amp;rsquo;s the code I used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-R&#34;&gt;library(tidyverse)
library(stringr)
library(pdftools)
library(tidytext)
library(ggraph)
library(igraph)

# create empty df
bigram_df &amp;lt;- tibble(word1 = character(), word2 = character(), 
                    n = numeric(), report_num = numeric())

# loop through each capstone pdf
for(k in 1:38){
  
  # parse text from capstone pdf
  report_text &amp;lt;- pdf_text(str_c(&amp;quot;reports/capstone&amp;quot;, k,&amp;quot;.pdf&amp;quot;))
  
  # unnest text into bigrams
  report_bigrams &amp;lt;- tibble(chapter = report_text) %&amp;gt;%
    unnest_tokens(bigram, chapter,token = &amp;quot;ngrams&amp;quot;, n = 2)
  
  # split bigrams into separate columns
  bigrams_sep &amp;lt;- report_bigrams %&amp;gt;% 
    separate(bigram, c(&amp;quot;word1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;word2&amp;quot;), sep = &amp;quot; &amp;quot;)
  
  # filter out stopwords, numbers, dupes; add count and report number
  bigrams_filtered &amp;lt;- bigrams_sep %&amp;gt;% 
    filter(!word1 %in% stop_words$word) %&amp;gt;% 
    filter(!word2 %in% stop_words$word) %&amp;gt;% 
    filter(!str_detect(word1, &amp;quot;[0-9]&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;% 
    filter(!str_detect(word2, &amp;quot;[0-9]&amp;quot;)) %&amp;gt;% 
    filter(word1 != word2) %&amp;gt;%
    count(word1, word2, sort = TRUE) %&amp;gt;%
    mutate(report_num = k)
  
  # add to df
  bigram_df &amp;lt;- bind_rows(bigram_df, bigrams_filtered)
  
}

# prep data for graphing; only count bigrams w/ n &amp;gt; 20
bigram_graph &amp;lt;- bigram_df %&amp;gt;% 
  filter(n &amp;gt; 20) %&amp;gt;% 
  graph_from_data_frame()

# set arrow type
a &amp;lt;- grid::arrow(type = &amp;quot;closed&amp;quot;, length = unit(.15, &amp;quot;inches&amp;quot;))

set.seed(23)

# plot bigram graph
ggraph(bigram_graph, layout = &amp;quot;fr&amp;quot;) +
  geom_edge_link(aes(edge_alpha = n), show.legend = FALSE,
                 arrow = a, end_cap = circle(.03, &#39;inches&#39;)) +
  geom_node_point(color = &amp;quot;lightblue&amp;quot;, size = 3) +
  geom_node_text(aes(label = name), vjust = 1, hjust = 1) +
  theme_void()

# save plot
ggsave(&amp;quot;figures/capstone_bigrams.png&amp;quot;, width = 12, height = 8, units = &amp;quot;in&amp;quot;)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/capstone_text_analysis/master/figures/capstone_bigrams.png&#34; alt=&#34;capstone bigrams&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting plot paints a nice picture of what SDP Fellows wrote about in their Capstone Reports. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of focus on college readiness and teacher effectiveness, which were two of the &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; on the SDP website, but it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to see what other words were frequently tied to those phrases. It also helps to see what some of the less-popular topics covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;tidytext&lt;/code&gt; package is a ton of fun to work with - I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to using it more and finding new sources of text to analyze!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDP Convening 2017</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-22-sdp-convening-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 22:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-22-sdp-convening-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was my second year attending the Strategic Data Project (SDP) Convening, the annual gathering of SDP Fellows and other education data nerds. There’s a ton of great content and conversation during the three days of Convening, here are some of the highlights from my perspective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/rickhess99&#34;&gt;Rick Hess&lt;/a&gt; kicked off the 2017 Convening with a brief talk on his latest book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Letters-Education-Reformer-Educational-Innovations/dp/1682530221&#34;&gt;Letters to a Young Education Reformer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. His writing has been a big influence on my thinking when it comes to education policy, so it was pretty great hearing him speak in person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really enjoyed hearing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/mpolikoff&#34;&gt;Morgan Polikoff&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gse.harvard.edu/faculty/thomas-kane&#34;&gt;Tom Kane&lt;/a&gt;, and Eric Hirsch (ED of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edreports.org&#34;&gt;EdReports&lt;/a&gt;) discuss their work on curricular materials. Helping schools select higher-quality textbooks can have a significant impact on student learning - states and districts would be wise to pay attention to the work they&amp;rsquo;re doing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As is tradition at Convening, there is always a performance by a group of students after dinner on Thursday evening. This year, we were honored with readings from some of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.826boston.org&#34;&gt;student authors from 826 Boston&lt;/a&gt;. Those kids are impressive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It was great to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://opensdp.github.io&#34;&gt;Open SDP&lt;/a&gt; launch on the final day of Convening. The entire SDP community (and more) will benefit from this open source approach to education data analysis. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to contributing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left the 2017 SDP Convening with many new ideas for improving how my team can apply our analytic skills to improve outcomes for students in Kentucky and beyond. Based on that alone, I&amp;rsquo;d call this year&amp;rsquo;s Convening a success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School choice via U-Haul</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-02-17-school-choice-via-uhaul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 13:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-02-17-school-choice-via-uhaul/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/thinkschools&#34;&gt;Alex Hernandez&lt;/a&gt; argued that 43 percent of children in the United States are benefiting from school choice. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.the74million.org/article/hernandez-devos-should-tell-her-critics-all-kids-deserve-school-choice-just-like-theirs-have&#34;&gt;In The 74, he wrote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;School districts assign children to public schools based on where they live. Then, the world’s largest game of musical chairs begins. The families of 24 million students find ways around their forced assignments to get the schools they want for their kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest school choice group is families who move to a new neighborhood to change their assigned school. They represent an estimated 8.2 million students, about one third of all school choosers. To be clear: The most popular way to choose a school in America is to literally move your family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This led me to wonder: what kinds of families are able to choose a school for their child by moving? Thankfully, Hernandez shows his work in &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@thinkschools/the-74-million-hernandez-devos-should-tell-her-critics-all-kids-deserve-school-choice-just-like-21d250c48e0f#.r6scv7i9l&#34;&gt;a Medium post&lt;/a&gt;, revealing the specific NCES reports he used to generate his estimates. His data comes from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nces.ed.gov/nhes/dataproducts.asp&#34;&gt;NCES National Household Education Surveys Program&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the Parent and Family Involvement in Education (PFI) survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, I was at an &lt;a href=&#34;http://sdp.cepr.harvard.edu&#34;&gt;SDP workshop&lt;/a&gt; and heard from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alex_j_bowers&#34;&gt;Alex Bowers&lt;/a&gt; on the kinds of research you can do with publicly-available education data, including NCES surveys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this coincidence as a sign to take the advice of one Alex (Bowers) and extend the work of another Alex (Hernandez). All of the analysis below was performed using this publicly available data and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alspur/nces_household_survey&#34;&gt;the code is available on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-are-the-movers&#34;&gt;Who are the movers?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving isn’t cheap. Families with more financial resources are more able to absorb the costs associated with moving to a neighborhood with a more desirable zoned school. Generally, as household income rises, students are more likely to have moved to their neighborhood specifically for the school. The following graph shows how frequently parents responding to the NCES survey decided to move neighborhoods for a better school, broken down by household income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/nces_household_survey/master/figures/inc_move_pct.png&#34; alt=&#34;inc_move_pct&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The racial demographics of each income bracket vary. Higher-income movers are less racially diverse than lower-income movers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/nces_household_survey/master/figures/race_inc_move.png&#34; alt=&#34;race_in_move&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splitting the chart above by racial group, we can see how likely a family is to move given their race and their incomes. We can see that the groups most likely to move neighborhoods for better schools are white and Asian families with a six-figure household income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/nces_household_survey/master/figures/race_inc_move_pct.png&#34; alt=&#34;race_in_move_pct&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-the-most-popular-destinations-for-movers&#34;&gt;What are the most popular destinations for movers?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The public NCES survey data doesn’t include precise location data, but it does provide the &lt;strong&gt;type&lt;/strong&gt; of neighborhood where these families live. It’s not surprising to see that most movers head for the suburbs. For clarification on what separates a “suburb, large” from a “town, distant” check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://nces.ed.gov/surveys/ruraled/definitions.asp&#34;&gt;their definitions on the NCES website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/nces_household_survey/master/figures/zip_move.png&#34; alt=&#34;zip_move&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chart shows the volume of movers by their chosen destination and their household income. It’s pretty clear that affluent families overwhelmingly choose to move to either suburbs or “rural, fringe” areas, defined as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Census-defined rural territory that is less than or equal to 5 miles from an urbanized area, as well as rural territory that is less than or equal to 2.5 miles from an urban cluster&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/nces_household_survey/master/figures/inc_move_zip.png&#34; alt=&#34;inc_move_zip&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For lower-income families, suburbs are still a popular destination, but they are much more likely to choose cities or towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/nces_household_survey/master/figures/inc_move_zip_pct.png&#34; alt=&#34;inc_move_zip_pct&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mover destinations by race reveal a consistent preference for suburbs, with varying degrees of preference for other destination types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/nces_household_survey/master/figures/zip_race_move_pct.png&#34; alt=&#34;zip_race_move_pct&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only scratched the surface of what we can learn from this particular survey. It has a lot more information I’d like to investigate, including parents’ views on school quality, if their students are in their first-choice school, and more. The survey has also been administered in 2007, 2005, and 2003, so it would be interesting to track some of these patterns on both sides of the Great Recession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Publicly-available education data is pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM Is Counting on Its Bet on Watson</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-10-25-watson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 06:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-10-25-watson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, Watson isn&amp;rsquo;t just playing Jeopardy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the University of North Carolina School of Medicine, Watson was tested on 1,000 cancer diagnoses made by human experts. In 99 percent of them, Watson recommended the same treatment as the oncologists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 30 percent of the cases, Watson also found a treatment option the human doctors missed. Some treatments were based on research papers that the doctors had not read — more than 160,000 cancer research papers are published a year. Other treatment options might have surfaced in a new clinical trial the oncologists had not yet seen announced on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Watson read it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool to see the support Artificial Intelligence (AI) could provide to oncologists. As the research and knowledge base in medicine expands and increasing rates, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to expect every researcher to be up-to-date on the every study, technique, or drug released. AI can help doctors make better decisions by recommending treatments based on a significantly larger base of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Watson can help doctors, why couldn&amp;rsquo;t it also help teachers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, it&amp;rsquo;s not a question of if, but when teachers will get the same support from AI. Changing classroom practice based on education research has always been a challenge. Organizations like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deansforimpact.org&#34;&gt;Deans for Impact&lt;/a&gt; are doing great work to &lt;a href=&#34;http://deansforimpact.org/the_science_of_learning.html&#34;&gt;promote good instructional practice based on cognitive science literature&lt;/a&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;Watson for teachers&amp;rdquo; could help lower the barriers between high-quality cognitive science, education research, and instructional practice. It may still be years away, but it will certainly help more teachers make better decisions to support student growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Why Knowledge Matters</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-10-02-booknotes-why-knowledge-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 06:40:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-10-02-booknotes-why-knowledge-matters/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;E.D. Hirsch is a self-described &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hedgehog_and_the_Fox&#34;&gt;hedgehog&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; viewing the world through the lens of one big idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[T]he achievement gap is chiefly a knowledge gap and a language gap. It can be greatly ameliorated by knowledge-based schooling.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inverse of Hirsch&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;big idea&amp;rdquo; is the skills-based approach to education that drives instruction in the vast majority of American schools. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Schools-We-Need-Dont-Have/dp/0385495242/&#34;&gt;The Schools We Need &amp;amp; Why We Don&amp;rsquo;t Have Them&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; was my first introduction to the &amp;ldquo;knowledge vs. skills&amp;rdquo; debate. This book re-introduces Hirsch&amp;rsquo;s basic case and extends it based on new evidence from the world of cognitive science and the experience of French schools over the past several decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-idea&#34;&gt;The Big Idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading, critical thinking, and problem solving are not general skills that can be developed and applied to any context. Like most human skills, they are domain-specific, becoming stronger or weaker based on a person&amp;rsquo;s background knowledge of the topic. Hirsch recommends providing all students with a curriculum in the early grades that focuses on developing knowledge, not skills, to promote equity and achievement among all students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-passages&#34;&gt;Key Passages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many well-intentioned people, including educators, state that in the age of Google, it&amp;rsquo;s less important for students to learn a bunch of information they could just look up. Their belief is that we need to equip students with the critical thinking and problem solving skills to apply these tools to the problems they are tackling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hirsch provides a great deal of evidence to support the need focusing on building knowledge instead of generalizable skills, but the most powerful rebuttal to this line of thinking is his explanation of the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matthew_effect&#34;&gt;Matthew Effect&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in education:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference works, inlcluding those available on the Internet, are immensely valuable to already knowledgeable people. Google is not an equal-opportunity fact-finder; it rewards those already in the know. Instead of being an agent of equality, Google rewards cognitive insiders. It consolidates educational inequity. Just as it takes money to make money, it takes knowledge to gain knowldege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the book, Hirsch shows how the shift from a universal knowledge-based curriculum in France to a locally-determined and skills-focused approach in 1990 led to disastrous results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new localizing and indivudalizing of the schools had been proposed as a way of overcoming the reproduction of social stratification. But the educational results went the opposite way, intensifying inequalities. As the French data from 1987 to 2007 show, the new 1990 arrangements greatly intensified the social reproduction they were supposed to diminish. They systematically deprived poor children of the enabling knowledge that rich children had acquired from their home environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hirsch&amp;rsquo;s proposed solution, replacing a individual-focused reading curriculum based on &amp;ldquo;leveled readers&amp;rdquo; with a knowledge-centered communal curriculum, is paradoxically a better way to encourage students to develop as individuals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It must not be assumed that a different approach - whole-class instruction of real books and subject matters - means grey uniformity. On the contrary, real knowledge breeds real interest and individuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This principle is extended later in the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s in relation to the community that the individual develops. Only by mastering the shared knowledge and norms of the community can one diverge from those norms effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Core Knowledge curriculum, developed by Hirsch, is one approach to empowering students with a foundation of communal knowledge. He acknowledges that there can be &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; differentiation in early grade curricula based on local values while still building a strong foundation of knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rival elementary curriculums may reflect rival values but all responsible ones will exhibit a great deal of overlap - out of a sense of obligation to the children who will need knowledge represented by those words in order to function well in American society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;actionable-items&#34;&gt;Actionable Items&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hirsch makes a convincing case for the power of a content-rich, coherent, and cumulative curriculum to build a strong foundation of literacy. While &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brookings.edu/research/never-judge-a-book-by-its-cover-use-student-achievement-instead/&#34;&gt;research has shown the strong impact of a high-quality curriculum on student achievement&lt;/a&gt;, there&amp;rsquo;s a paucity of publicly available data on school curriculum. In some cases, &lt;a href=&#34;https://morganpolikoff.com/2016/01/14/an-awful-lot-of-districts-dont-know-what-textbooks-are-used-in-their-schools/&#34;&gt;districts may not even know&lt;/a&gt; which textbooks are being used in their classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can agree or disagree with the case Hirsch makes, but we should all be able to agree that curricular choices play an important role in student achievement. It would make sense to make information about those choices more transparent so that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Educators would know which schools/districts are using similar/identical approaches, creating opportunities for highly relevant cross-school/district collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researchers could evaluate the relative strength/weakness of curriculum implemented in public schools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;School boards and local school councils would have significantly more information to inform adoption/renewal of curriculum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of this is possible without transparent data on curriculum. Collecting information about such an important component of public education shouldn&amp;rsquo;t require a FOIA request.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blame the Elites for the Trump Phenomenon</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-09-18-blame-the-elites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-09-18-blame-the-elites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intelligence Squared hosts Oxford-style debates, with two teams supporting or opposing a motion. The motion of their most recent debate: blame the elites for the Trump phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&amp;rsquo;m for the motion, but I would encourage you to watch and decide for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Turned Upside Down</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-09-08-the-world-turned-upside-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 05:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-09-08-the-world-turned-upside-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 11 years of litigation, Judge Thomas Moukawsher &lt;a href=&#34;http://ctmirror.org/2016/09/07/judge-strikes-down-state-education-aid-choices-as-irrational/&#34;&gt;issued a seismic decision in the CCJEF school finance lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jud.ct.gov/CCJEFvRell.pdf&#34;&gt;the decision&lt;/a&gt;, Moukawsher not only eviscerated Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s school finance system, he also detailed flaws in the state&amp;rsquo;s approach to teacher evaluation, teacher compensation, the lack of clear definitions of success in elementary and secondary education, and gave the state 180 days to come up with a solution to all of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to digest, but here are my initial thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to see the ruling bring more attention to the distribution of funding than the overall allocation. As I argued nearly two years ago, &lt;a href=&#34;http://alspur.com/athoughtexperiment/&#34;&gt;actual appropriations are not driven by the ECS formula&lt;/a&gt;, leading to huge funding disparities (positive and negative) that affect thousands of students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sympathetic with the desire for better approaches to teacher evaluation and compensation, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure the order in this ruling is the best way to actually improve how those systems operate. To &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationalaffairs.com/publications/detail/the-missing-half-of-school-reform&#34;&gt;paraphrase Rick Hess&lt;/a&gt;, while judicial orders can make people do things, it cannot make people do those things well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The timeline is super-aggressive. Staffers at the Connecticut State Department of Education are going to have a busy winter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will the state&amp;rsquo;s proposed solution include magnets, charters, and/or other choice options? The state &lt;a href=&#34;http://alspur.com/outdated-funding-systems/&#34;&gt;already spends a significant amount of funding&lt;/a&gt; on these schools and the ruling sounds like a mandate for a comprehensive solution. It will be interesting to see how they address this question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s much more to digest in this decision. While the plaintiffs got a partial victory, they&amp;rsquo;re about to learn an important lesson:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning is easy. &lt;a href=&#34;http://genius.com/7856447&#34;&gt;Governing&amp;rsquo;s harder.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a free distributed data collection &#34;app&#34; with R and Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-08-29-distributed-data-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 06:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-08-29-distributed-data-collection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A really neat concept that reminds me of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://alspur.com/time-tracking/&#34;&gt;time tracking method&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stat.ubc.ca/~jenny/&#34;&gt;Jenny Bryan&lt;/a&gt;, developer of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jennybc/googlesheets&#34;&gt;google sheets R package&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/jennybc/googlesheets-talk-at-user2015&#34;&gt;gave a talk&lt;/a&gt; at Use2015 about the package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that got me most excited about the package was an example she gave in her talk of using the Google Sheets package for data collection at ultimate frisbee tournaments. One reason is that I used to play a little ultimate &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pbase.com/jmlane/image/76852417&#34;&gt;back in the day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another is that her idea is an amazing one for producing cool public health applications. One of the major issues with public health is being able to do distributed data collection cheaply, easily, and reproducibly. So I decided to write a little tutorial on how one could use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/sheets/about/&#34;&gt;Google Sheets&lt;/a&gt; and R to create a free distributed data collecton “app” for public health (or anything else really).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of hype around &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; in every field, including education, but I&amp;rsquo;m convinced there are many interesting questions that could be investigated at the school/district level with a &amp;ldquo;small data&amp;rdquo; approach supported by this workflow. There are obvious limitations - you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to put individual student/teacher data in a public Google Sheet - but it&amp;rsquo;s worth thinking about the kinds of programs/practices in schools that could benefit from research supported by distributed data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Orientation and Educational Performance</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-08-22-long-term-orientation-and-educational-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 08:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-08-22-long-term-orientation-and-educational-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If there&amp;rsquo;s one common thread between &lt;a href=&#34;http://educationnext.org/taking-a-lesson-from-the-boys-in-the-boat-and-aiming-for-swing/&#34;&gt;Robin Lake relating &lt;em&gt;The Boys in the Boat&lt;/em&gt; to schools&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://relinquishment.org/2016/08/21/an-alternative-interpretation-of-the-fryer-dobbie-texas-charter-study/&#34;&gt;Neerav Kingsland on a recent charter study&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://educationnext.org/growing-up-poor-and-white-in-america-a-view-from-the-inside/&#34;&gt;Robert Pondiscio on &lt;em&gt;Hillbilly Elegy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s that culture plays a huge role in education. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nber.org/papers/w22541&#34;&gt;A new NBER Working Paper&lt;/a&gt; provides powerful evidence that it may be even more critical than was previously understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors examine the performance of first and second generation immigrant students in Florida to understand the relationship between the &amp;ldquo;long-term orientation&amp;rdquo; of the cultures they come from to their educational outcomes. They find that students from families from countries with a high degree of long-term orientation score higher &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; grow more over time than similar students from countries with lower long-term orientation. They also are more likely to have better attendance, fewer disciplinary incidents, and enroll in more advanced classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put the size of the &amp;ldquo;long-term orientation&amp;rdquo; effect into context, the authors note that their data showed that a student of a mother holding a college degree scored 40% higher in math than the child of a high school dropout. The same data shows that holding everything else equal, moving from the lowest long-term orientation measure (Puerto Rico) to the highest (South Korea) translates to a &lt;strong&gt;73% higher math score&lt;/strong&gt;, almost twice the impact of a parent with a college education compared to a high school dropout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education reform is often focused on factors that can be addressed via policy change, like human capital management, standards/curriculum, and school governance/accountability. Yet as challenging as those issues are, we can&amp;rsquo;t ignore the power of culture, and more specifically, values that support delayed gratification. &lt;a href=&#34;https://edexcellence.net/events/education-for-upward-mobility&#34;&gt;Fordham&amp;rsquo;s Education for Upward Mobility&lt;/a&gt; conference is a start, but given the power of culture to impact educational outcomes, this conversation deserves a more prominent place within the ed reform community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESSA and the Administrative State</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-08-18-essa-and-the-administrative-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 06:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-08-18-essa-and-the-administrative-state/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/chadaldeman&#34;&gt;Chad Aldeman&lt;/a&gt; on the delegation of policy making in ESSA:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress was able to reach broad bipartisan agreement on ESSA mainly because it punted on a number of key policy questions. Any reading of ESSA leaves one wondering what exactly Congress meant when it asked states to “meaningfully differentiate” among schools, when it required that states give “substantial weight” to each indicator, or when it stipulated that academic indicators count for “much greater weight” than non-academic ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I am pleased that ESSA will give states more latitude to develop school accountability models, I share Aldeman&amp;rsquo;s concern that we don&amp;rsquo;t really know how &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; of the candidates for president would approach ESSA rule making. This exemplifies a long-term trend in which Congress cedes power to the administrative agencies tasked with implementing legislation - a topic covered in the most recent episode of &lt;a href=&#34;https://overcast.fm/+EcI5qucGU&#34;&gt;The Federalist Radio Hour&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this habit is not broken, we will continue to find ourselves lamenting the uncertain implementation of major legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregation Theory and Education</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-08-14-aggregation-theory-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 06:15:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-08-14-aggregation-theory-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Five years ago, Marc Andressen took to the pages of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460.html&#34;&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/a&gt; to describe how software was &amp;ldquo;eating the world&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;More and more major businesses and industries are being run on software and delivered as online services—from movies to agriculture to national defense. Many of the winners are Silicon Valley-style entrepreneurial technology companies that are invading and overturning established industry structures. Over the next 10 years, I expect many more industries to be disrupted by software, with new world-beating Silicon Valley companies doing the disruption in more cases than not.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to come up with a list of examples of this prediction coming true, from taxis (Uber) to hotels (AirBnB), but software-driven disruption has yet to significantly change K-12 education. Existing online education offerings, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.khanacademy.org/&#34;&gt;Khan Academy&lt;/a&gt;, show promise, but few would argue that their impact on K-12 education to date could be described as anything close to &amp;ldquo;disruptive.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://jaypgreene.com/2016/08/12/online-courses-may-not-be-the-way-of-the-future/&#34;&gt;Jay P. Greene explains&lt;/a&gt; why all-online education has failed to gain traction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online courses appear to be less effective in getting the average student to learn and I suspect the problem is that teaching online is less able to create social communities and authentic relationships that are necessary to motivate students.  Having a human being in front of students who would be disappointed if students did not learn the material seems important and something that online instruction has not been able to simulate.  Students appear to be better motivated to learn when they have an in-person, authentic relationship with a teacher and when they try to please that teacher by working hard to learn.  Digital instruction or a human being on the other side of the internet may not be able to create that same relationship and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question remains: &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; K-12 education is going to be disrupted by software, what would it look like? Is there a way to combine the scalability of software with the power of strong interpersonal relationships?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delving deeper into the disruption of other industries might give us an answer. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/benthompson&#34;&gt;Ben Thompson&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2015/aggregation-theory/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aggregation Theory&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a great framework to understand how the Internet is changing entire sectors of our economy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The value chain for any given consumer market is divided into three parts: suppliers, distributors, and consumers/users. The best way to make outsize profits in any of these markets is to either gain a horizontal monopoly in one of the three parts or to integrate two of the parts such that you have a competitive advantage in delivering a vertical solution. In the pre-Internet era the latter depended on controlling distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, printed newspapers were the primary means of delivering content to consumers in a given geographic region, so newspapers integrated backwards into content creation (i.e. supplier) and earned outsized profits through the delivery of advertising. A similar dynamic existed in all kinds of industries, such as book publishers (distribution capabilities integrated with control of authors), video (broadcast availability integrated with purchasing content), taxis (dispatch capabilities integrated with medallions and car ownership), hotels (brand trust integrated with vacant rooms), and more. Note how the distributors in all of these industries integrated backwards into supply: there have always been far more users/consumers than suppliers, which means that in a world where transactions are costly owning the supplier relationship provides significantly more leverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamental disruption of the Internet has been to turn this dynamic on its head. First, the Internet has made distribution (of digital goods) free, neutralizing the advantage that pre-Internet distributors leveraged to integrate with suppliers. Secondly, the Internet has made transaction costs zero, making it viable for a distributor to integrate forward with end users/consumers at scale.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applying &lt;em&gt;Aggregation Theory&lt;/em&gt;, K-12 schools can be viewed as an industry that integrates the supply and distribution of educational content. Like newspapers, this integrated product is limited to a certain geographic area. It also helps us to understand that most popular education reforms only seek to improve certain aspects of this relationship instead of fundamentally changing it. For example, charter schools may introduce more competition for students (customers), but they still (generally) operate with the same model of integrated supply and distribution of educational content to students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some tech companies are trying to flip the equation by integrating the delivery of educational content more directly with the student experience, making the actual content more of a modular component. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.apple.com/education/products/&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/edu/products/productivity-tools/classroom/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://summitbasecamp.org/&#34;&gt;Facebook (in collaboration with Summit Charter Schools)&lt;/a&gt; each offer products that allow teachers to provide a digital classroom experience for their students while also maintaining in-person relationships. This may help them avoid the pitfalls of the all-online education efforts identified by Green, but can any of them truly change the integration of content and delivery in K-12 education?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the three large tech companies, I think the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/08/10/technology/facebook-helps-develop-software-that-puts-students-in-charge-of-their-lesson-plans.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;Facebook/Summit approach&lt;/a&gt; has the most potential to deliver &lt;em&gt;Aggregation Theory&lt;/em&gt;-style disruption. The online classroom products of Apple and Google are mostly abstractions of a traditional classroom in the cloud: teachers assign work to each student, then students submit it by a given due date. All of this happens online, but everyone in the class is still on the same timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Facebook/Summit collaboration, named &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.summitbasecamp.org&#34;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;, takes &lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2015/netflix-and-the-conservation-of-attractive-profits/&#34;&gt;a more Netflix-ian approach&lt;/a&gt; to delivering content. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it&amp;rsquo;s described on the Basecamp website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Students work through playlists of content at their own pace and take assessments on demand. They also work with teachers to set short-term and long-term goals and connect these back to their daily actions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Facebook/Summit approach, time is no longer a constraint for students that have already mastered certain content, nor is it a limitation for students that may need more time to fully grasp a concept before moving on to the next lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This represents a fundamental shift in the relationship between students,how they learn, and  the role of educators in supporting students through that process. The Basecamp platform is still in its infancy and has much room to develop, particularly to address the needs of students with ß or limited English proficiency. However, we should still recognize the potential this approach could have in changing how K-12 schools operate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why American Schools Are Even More Unequal Than We Thought</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-08-12-why-some-american-schools-are-more-unequal-than-we-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 14:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-08-12-why-some-american-schools-are-more-unequal-than-we-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using data to inform our conversations about public school performance is a good idea, but too often, the measures we use are reduced to imprecise terms like &amp;ldquo;proficiency,&amp;rdquo; which can carry several different meanings when describing a local, state, or national assessment&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/dynarski&#34;&gt;Susan Dynarski&lt;/a&gt; notes in The Upshot, this is also a common problem with the most-frequently used proxy for &amp;ldquo;poverty&amp;rdquo; in education, Free/Reduced Price Lunch (FRPL) eligibility:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nearly half of students nationwide are eligible for a subsidized meal in school. Children whose families earn less than 185 percent of the poverty threshold are eligible for a reduced-price lunch, while those below 130 percent get a free lunch. For a family of four, the cutoffs are $32,000 for a free lunch and $45,000 for a reduced-price one. By way of comparison, median household income in the United States was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.census.gov/content/dam/Census/library/publications/2015/demo/p60-252.pdf&#34;&gt;about $54,000&lt;/a&gt; in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eligibility for subsidized school meals is clearly a blunt indicator of economic status. But that is the measure that policy makers, educators and researchers rely on when they gauge gaps in academic achievement in schools, districts and states.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, this means that when we refer to FRPL students as &amp;ldquo;economically disadvantaged,&amp;rdquo; we&amp;rsquo;re really painting with a broad brush. Thankfully, Dynarski and her co-author, Katherine Michelmore, devised a way to use current FRPL data to produce &lt;a href=&#34;http://users.nber.org/~dynarski/w22474.pdf&#34;&gt;a more precise picture of student economic disadvantage&lt;/a&gt;: instead of looking at FRPL-eligibility in the current school year, we can use longitudinal datasets to look at how many &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; a student has been FRPL-eligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept is simple. If you were comparing two fifth grade students, student A and student B. If student A has been FRPL-eligible for a year and student B has been FRPL-eligible for five years, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that student B has a greater economic disadvantage than student A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynarski continues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one ever actively decided that eligibility for subsidized meals was the best way to measure students’ economic disadvantage. The metric was widely available and became by default the standard way to distinguish between poorer and richer children. But it was always an imprecise measure, and we can do better at little cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen &lt;a href=&#34;https://morganpolikoff.com/2016/07/12/a-letter-to-the-u-s-department-of-education/&#34;&gt;researchers stand up to advocate for better ways to quantify &amp;ldquo;proficiency&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; - I hope we see a similar movement by researchers to advocate for better measures of poverty. Supporting Dynarski&amp;rsquo;s approach would be a good (and cost-efficient!) step in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;This is a particular problem when NAEP results are released. Just remember, &lt;a href=&#34;https://morganpolikoff.com/2015/10/06/friends-dont-let-friends-misuse-naep-data/&#34;&gt;friends don&amp;rsquo;t let friends engage in misNAEPery&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - The Checklist Manifesto</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-08-11-booknotes-the-checklist-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 06:43:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-08-11-booknotes-the-checklist-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Books have always been important to me. My grandmother was a librarian and as she babysat me, I was able to spend hundreds, if not thousands, of hours searching, consuming, and falling in love with books. That passion continues today, but I find that I have less time to devote to extended, deep periods of reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cgpgrey.com/blog/bird-by-bird&#34;&gt;CGP Grey&amp;rsquo;s lead and start publicly sharing notes on books I&amp;rsquo;ve read&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s his explanation of why he started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to attempt, for a little while anyway, to make public some of my notes from some of the books that I&amp;rsquo;ve read. This is partly because people are forever asking what I&amp;rsquo;m reading, but it&amp;rsquo;s mostly as a way to try and encourage myself to read both more deeply and more frequently &amp;ndash; a target I have been trying, and failing, to hit for all my adult life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All projects and hobbies of mine eventually die from lack of attention if they cannot serve multiple purposes. So it is my hope that these notes will add even more reason to engage more frequently with long-form writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t anything close to a public clamor for my reading list, but I do hope that this practice helps me with his second goal - increasing my incentives to read books with more depth and more frequency. Additionally, I hope that formalizing this process will help me draw better connections between the books I read and what it could mean for education and/or individual productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, I&amp;rsquo;m going to apply Grey&amp;rsquo;s template to the last book I finished, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Checklist-Manifesto-How-Things-Right/dp/0312430000/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Checklist Manifesto&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-big-idea&#34;&gt;The Big Idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professionals of all varieties - programmers, doctors, teachers, pilots, etc. - perform cognitively demanding tasks on regular basis in high-stakes settings. They apply the skills they&amp;rsquo;ve honed through training, their understanding of their field, and their general experience to execute complex tasks. But no matter how competent or prepared these professionals are, they still make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In a complex environment, experts are up against two main difficulties. The first is the fallibility of human memory and attention, especially when it comes to mundane, routine matters that are easily overlooked under the strain of more pressing events.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A further difficulty, just as insidious, is that people can lull themselves into skipping steps even when they remember them. In complex processes, after all, certain steps don’t always matter. Perhaps the elevator controls on airplanes are usually unlocked and a check is pointless most of the time. Perhaps measuring all four vital signs uncovers a worrisome issue in only one out of fifty patients. “This has never been a problem before,” people say. Until one day it is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with confidence in your ability to practice your profession, but it does breed a degree hubris that even when seemingly benign, can lead to significant errors. Gwande provides several examples of this in the medical field, where skipping seemingly obvious steps can lead to someone having their right knee opened up even if they&amp;rsquo;re in for an ACL repair on their left knee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not hard to see how this could translate to the classroom. A teacher might typically use exit tickets to gauge how much students understood the concepts taught in each lesson. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine a scenario where the teacher assumes a lesson went well and forgoes this step. This may only happen once in a while, but it could be the case that while the lesson seemed to go well, students actually misunderstood the concept that was taught. It&amp;rsquo;s a much lower-stakes situation than a botched surgery, but even this small disruption could alter the success and pacing of future lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of minimizing mistakes in routine processes is also applicable to data analysis. Each data analysis project involves follows the broad format of importing, cleaning, transforming, and reporting data. If small steps along the way aren&amp;rsquo;t double-checked, a tiny error can lead to significant problems with the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gwande stresses that using checklists to minimize error isn&amp;rsquo;t meant to dumb down the work of professionals. Instead, he argues that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is common to misconceive how checklists function in complex lines of work. They are not comprehensive how-to guides, whether for building a skyscraper or getting a plane out of trouble. They are quick and simple tools aimed to buttress the skills of expert professionals. And by remaining swift and usable and resolutely modest, they are saving thousands upon thousands of lives.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-passages&#34;&gt;Key Passages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the B-17 bomber was developed in the mid-1930&amp;rsquo;s, it was the most complex aircraft ever built. It had four engines when nearly every plane had one or maybe two engines. This, along with the plane&amp;rsquo;s other features, made the task of piloting it incredibly complex. The first time the plane was tested, it crashed shortly after takeoff not due to any mechanical issue, but to pilot error. The new design was simply too complex for one person to manage on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development on the plane continued and another test flight was scheduled. This time, the pilots developed what is now a staple of aviation: a checklist. It was concise, but it ultimately helped flight crews man the B-17 without incident from that point forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found this to be a terrific example of intellectual humility by the test pilots. They were extremely well-trained, but they were willing to admit to themselves that while they were experts, their brains weren&amp;rsquo;t reliable enough to ensure perfect execution every single time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Substantial parts of what software designers, financial managers, firefighters, police officers, lawyers, and most certainly clinicians do are now too complex for them to carry out reliably from memory alone. Multiple fields, in other words, have become too much airplane for one person to fly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educators and data analysts alike find themselves with &amp;ldquo;too much airplane&amp;rdquo; right now. We need to have the humility to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admit that these are jobs we can&amp;rsquo;t do alone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop tools to help overcome the problem of &amp;ldquo;too much airplane.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;actionable-items&#34;&gt;Actionable Items&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You want people to make sure to get the stupid stuff right. Yet you also want to leave room for craft and judgment and the ability to respond to unexpected difficulties that arise along the way”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checklists must strike an important balance. They need to cover enough critical points in a process to minimize the &amp;ldquo;stupid stuff&amp;rdquo; that could happen, but they also need the flexibility and brevity to be useful in a real-world setting. Gwande explains the difference between a good checklist and a bad one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Bad checklists are vague and imprecise. They are too long; they are hard to use; they are impractical. They are made by desk jockeys with no awareness of the situations in which they are to be deployed. They treat the people using the tools as dumb and try to spell out every single step. They turn people’s brains off rather than turn them on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good checklists, on the other hand, are precise. They are efficient, to the point, and easy to use even in the most difficult situations. They do not try to spell out everything—a checklist cannot fly a plane. Instead, they provide reminders of only the most critical and important steps—the ones that even the highly skilled professionals using them could miss. Good checklists are, above all, practical.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After developing a good, concise checklist comes the most critical step: implementation. As Gwande first developed his surgical checklist, he practiced using it with his surgical team to figure out what worked, what didn&amp;rsquo;t, and how they could improve it &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; using it in an actual surgical setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the checklist was tested, it needed to gain adoption with other surgeons and their teams. Gwande started introducing it to chief surgeons - the idea was that if a hospital&amp;rsquo;s leadership was able to embrace the change, others would follow. This is exactly what happened, and the incidence of surgical errors began to drop. But then something else began to happen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Spot surveys of random staff members coming out of surgery after the checklist was in effect did indeed report a significant increase in the level of communication. There was also a notable correlation between teamwork scores and results for patients—the greater the improvement in teamwork, the greater the drop in complications.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The checklist process actually helped keep surgical teams more aware of what each person was doing by establishing a template for regular communication between everyone in the operating room. It&amp;rsquo;s an example of the hidden benefit of checklists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just ticking boxes is not the ultimate goal here. Embracing a culture of teamwork and discipline is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up checklists can not only improve processes, it can help build stronger teams. For educators and analysts alike, that&amp;rsquo;s a goal worthy of pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tinkering</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-08-10-tinkering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 09:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-08-10-tinkering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most recent episode of &lt;em&gt;Mad Dogs &amp;amp; Englishmen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; starts off with a discussion of buying and assembling and AR-15 from scratch. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting process, but the conversation took an even more interesting turn as they focused on the decline of a tinkering ethos in our society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The machines and devices we use are often too complex to repair, disassemble, or customize. If you open the hood of your car, you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see or even access many of the most critical parts - you&amp;rsquo;ll most likely see a series of injection-molded plastic meant to not only protect but to discourage amateur tinkering. It is more likely that you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to tinker with your car by software (via OBD-II compatible devices like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.automatic.com/home/&#34;&gt;Automatic&lt;/a&gt;) than by mechanical manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding how to tinker/hack software is an increasingly valuable skill, but we should also recognize and cultivate the ability to take apart, assemble, fix, and customize physical objects. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maker_culture&#34;&gt;Maker Movement&lt;/a&gt; is a great example of keeping mechanical tinkering alive by encouraging kids and adults alike to get their hands dirty by blending both digital and physical craftsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more of our lives become digitized, I hope that we continue to find ways to maintain some form of physical tinkering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mad Dogs and Englishmen&lt;/em&gt; is a podcast featuring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationalreview.com&#34;&gt;National Review&lt;/a&gt; writers &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/kevinNR&#34;&gt;Kevin Williamson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/charlescwcooke&#34;&gt;Charles C.W. Cooke&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellectuals are Freaks</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-08-09-intellectuals-are-freaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-08-09-intellectuals-are-freaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Lind on the weakness of intellectuals&amp;rsquo; approach to inequality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The views of intellectuals about social reform tend to be warped by professional and personal biases, as well. In the U.S. the default prescription for inequality and other social problems among professors, pundits, and policy wonks alike tends to be: More education! Successful intellectuals get where they are by being good at taking tests and by going to good schools. It is only natural for them to generalize from their own highly atypical life experiences and propose that society would be better off if everyone went to college — natural, but still stupid and lazy. Most of the jobs in advanced economies — a majority of them in the service sector — do not require higher education beyond a little vocational training. Notwithstanding automation, for the foreseeable future janitors will vastly outnumber professors, and if the wages of janitors are too low then other methods — unionization, the restriction of low-wage immigration, a higher minimum wage — make much more sense than enabling janitors to acquire BAs, much less MAs and Ph.Ds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a member of the very intellectual class Lind describes. I share his concern that our &amp;ldquo;intellectual class&amp;rdquo; is too isolated from the experiences of the majority of our fellow citizens and that this can lead to ideas/policies that would work great for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/12/books/review/charles-murray-examines-the-white-working-class-in-coming-apart.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;Belmont but fail to address the needs of Fishtown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But does that mean the &amp;ldquo;intellectual class&amp;rdquo; solution of &amp;ldquo;more education&amp;rdquo; is the wrong answer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year, fewer jobs are available to those with only a high school degree. If we want to expand opportunity for working class Americans, it means ensuring a greater portion earn a BA - it also means that we need more people completing career/technical education and earning 2-year degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lind argues for short-term protectionist solutions to address low wages: more unionization, less immigration, and higher minimum wages. These may sound attractive, but they are ultimately stopgap measures that don&amp;rsquo;t address the systemic challenge in our economy, illustrated in the graphic below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Good visualization of the unequal distribution of the economic benefits of globalization. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/9fhx0Od6UM&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/9fhx0Od6UM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Marc Porter Magee (@marcportermagee) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/marcportermagee/status/747955262493958144&#34;&gt;June 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did wages for the Western working class stagnate while the Asian middle class grew just as much as the income of the most affluent? As Yuval Levin explains in &lt;a href=&#34;https://itun.es/us/MtS-_.l&#34;&gt;The Fractured Republic&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In the 1950s, the nation produced more than half of the world’s total manufactured goods—a mind-boggling, if obviously transitory, advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The equality of the postwar era was a unique moment in American history, subsidized in large part by the devastating impact of WWII on competing economies. As other nations rebuilt and technology facilitated the rise of globalization, the wage premium for American labor withered away. Protectionist policies can only attempt to insulate against this trend - they don&amp;rsquo;t address the fundamental challenge that work historically performed by high school graduates in the US can now increasingly be performed more cheaply abroad or by robots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The long-term solution is obvious: more education (both career and college oriented) to help more people access highly-skilled jobs with high wages, but we also need to consider shorter-term solutions to help make this transition less disruptive &lt;em&gt;without resorting to protectionism&lt;/em&gt;. This will certainly involve a re-thinking of our social welfare system, either by re-imagining &lt;a href=&#34;http://abetterway.speaker.gov&#34;&gt;A Better Way&lt;/a&gt; to run our current system, or replacing it with something more radical, like a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aei.org/press/in-our-hands-a-plan-to-replace-the-welfare-state-by-charles-murray/&#34;&gt;Universal Basic Income&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I disagree with Lind&amp;rsquo;s proposed solution to inequality, I agree that more members of the &amp;ldquo;intellectual class&amp;rdquo; need to get outside of our bubbles to better understand the lives of working class Americans. Our nation is currently a &lt;a href=&#34;https://itun.es/us/MtS-_.l&#34;&gt;fractured republic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://itun.es/us/2K5mA.l&#34;&gt;coming apart&lt;/a&gt; - those of us in the &amp;ldquo;intellectual class&amp;rdquo; need to actively work to reverse the isolation we experience and cultivate more relationships and empathy for people of all backgrounds in our society.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Tracking</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-07-29-time-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 20:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-07-29-time-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I tweeted this out earlier today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Insights from time tracking: I need to do more &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/rstats?src=hash&#34;&gt;#rstats&lt;/a&gt; programming on Thursday/Friday afternoons. Also, mtgs suck. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/14dFtGNubP&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/14dFtGNubP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alex Spurrier (@alspur) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alspur/status/759097342435917824&#34;&gt;July 29, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do I have time tracking charts that break down when I do certain kinds of work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A book (&lt;a href=&#34;https://itun.es/us/mqIh7.l&#34;&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt;) and a podcast (&lt;a href=&#34;http://relay.fm/cortex&#34;&gt;Cortex&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that the ability to focus is important to the work I do, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://itun.es/us/mqIh7.l&#34;&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt; by Cal Newport helped articulate precisely &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s extremely important to cultivate the ability to perform &amp;ldquo;deep work.&amp;rdquo; I recommend reading the book, but the tl;dr is that in order to succeed in today&amp;rsquo;s economy, one needs to be able to perform extremely cognitively demanding work with speed and quality. In order to accomplish that kind of work, one needs to be able to &amp;ldquo;focus intently without distraction.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constant stream of email, texts, meetings, and phone calls that are commonplace in modern offices help keep us informed and connected to our coworkers, but it often prevents us from being able to maintain sustained periods of focus on cognitively demanding tasks. Newport makes several recommendations to combat distraction, but I found the most helpful advice was to schedule every minute of my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of scheduling every minute of your day isn&amp;rsquo;t to hold yourself to an itinerary without any allowance for deviations. Instead, it&amp;rsquo;s a way to be more intentional about how you&amp;rsquo;re spending your time. More importantly, it can help you better track the amount of deep work you&amp;rsquo;re actually accomplishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently use my calendar as a guide for how I&amp;rsquo;m going to spend my week. There are always meetings I have to work around, but every other minute at work is allocated to a specific type of work. Despite my best intentions, reality doesn&amp;rsquo;t always align with the calendar I set, so I needed another system to help me better track the work I actually accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter &lt;a href=&#34;http://relay.fm/cortex&#34;&gt;Cortex&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cortex is a podcast featuring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/imyke&#34;&gt;Myke Hurley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/cgpgrey&#34;&gt;C.G.P. Grey&lt;/a&gt; talking about how they get their work done. In their third episode, &lt;a href=&#34;cortex3lcp&#34;&gt;Grey reveals&lt;/a&gt; that he uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/gSEQV.i&#34;&gt;Launch Center Pro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/XoZpx.i&#34;&gt;Due&lt;/a&gt; as a time tracking system. The workflow goes something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a 40 minute timer in Due &amp;amp; begin working&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the timer goes off, open Launch Center Pro, which has several actions associated with a specific type of work you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trigger the action associated with the work you just performed, which adds a row to a spreadsheet detailing the time and type of work you&amp;rsquo;re doing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reset timer and continue working.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any good nerd, I&amp;rsquo;ve tweaked this system a little. I&amp;rsquo;ve integrated &lt;a href=&#34;https://appsto.re/us/BTL91.i&#34;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; actions with the Launch Center Pro actions so I can capture a little more context about the work I&amp;rsquo;m doing. I also use &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34;&gt;R Markdown&lt;/a&gt; to convert the spreadsheet of my time tracking data into charts in a PDF that help me understand how I&amp;rsquo;m spending my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This took a little bit of work to set up, but it&amp;rsquo;s been extremely helpful. Every Friday afternoon, I look at the PDF produced by the R Markdown script I wrote a few months ago. It&amp;rsquo;s helped me realize how productive I am before 9am. I now make sure that before I leave the office, I&amp;rsquo;m clear on the work I want to tackle the first thing the following morning. Conversely, looking at the data also shows me I still have to work on making the afternoons on Thursdays and Fridays more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in improving your capacity for deep work, start with tracking your time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ezra Klein interviews Yuval Levin</title>
      <link>/blog/2016-07-19-ezra-klein-interviews-yuval-levin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 21:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016-07-19-ezra-klein-interviews-yuval-levin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a thoughtful, in-depth conversation that covers from the thesis of Levin&amp;rsquo;s latest book, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Fractured-Republic-Renewing-America%C2%92s-Individualism/dp/0465061966&#34;&gt;The Fractured Republic&lt;/a&gt;, his experience working in the Bush (43) Administration, the most interesting policy ideas on each side of the political spectrum, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/the-ezra-klein-show/id1081584611&#34;&gt;Ezra Klein Show&lt;/a&gt; episode I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to - I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to adding others to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://overcast.fm&#34;&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt; queue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The objective paradox</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-12-23-the-objective-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-12-23-the-objective-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/stop-trying-to-be-creative/&#34;&gt;This entire article&lt;/a&gt; on creativity is worth a read, but one passage in particular caught my attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one experiment a bipedal robot programmed to walk farther and farther actually ended up walking less far than one that simply was programmed to do something novel again and again, Stanley writes. Falling on the ground and flailing your legs doesn’t look much like walking, but it’s a good way to learn to oscillate, and oscillation is the most effective motion for walking. If you lock your objectives strictly on walking, you won’t hit that oscillation stepping stone. Stanley calls this the “objective paradox” — as soon as you create an objective, you ruin your ability to reach it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective paradox explains why NCLB&amp;rsquo;s approach to accountability failed. It asked our schools to &amp;ldquo;walk farther&amp;rdquo; without a full appreciation for the complexity of what it would take to accomplish the task. Some schools were able to respond to this challenge and many students benefited as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, far too many schools were not equipped to meet the goals set by NCLB. Instead of allowing schools to &amp;ldquo;flail and oscillate,&amp;rdquo; NCLB drove them to focus on getting one step further down the path. As many have acknowledged, this had the unintended consequence of forcing schools to divert too much focus too reading and math instruction at the expense of other subjects and priorities that may have actually contributed to better reading and math comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t to say that setting goals for reading and math achievement isn&amp;rsquo;t important, but to emphasize that too much focus on these goals can have a deleterious impact on student outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Education reformers (myself included) have an impatient desire for rapid change and improvement when we see public school system that fails to adequately serve students, particularly students of color, students with disabilities, and poor students. It&amp;rsquo;s a perfectly reasonable position - these children don&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury of time on their side. We are right to seek solutions now and not at some distant future date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, we need to temper that relentless drive to improve the quality of public education for all children with the humility to understand two constraints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t know what the perfect system looks like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progress won&amp;rsquo;t always be measured by annual, linear changes in math and reading scores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many high-performing schools already understand this. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/mpolikoff&#34;&gt;Morgan Polikoff&lt;/a&gt; recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://morganpolikoff.com/2015/12/11/my-visit-to-success-academies/&#34;&gt;visited Success Academies in NYC&lt;/a&gt; and observed that the instruction and culture of the school was nothing like the caricature of a test-obsessed, drill-and-kill school solely focused on boosting reading and math scores. Instead, he found that their primary goals for students in English/Language Arts are: &amp;ldquo;for students to 1) love literature and want to read, and 2) be able to understand what they’re reading.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polikoff also identifies several important structural elements that contribute to SA&amp;rsquo;s success. This includes a strong emphasis on student-led dialogue, excellent classroom management procedures, and an instructional culture that embraces feedback/coaching. None of those structural elements, taken on their own, would allow a school to achieve math and reading  results similar to SA, but developing these systems (or other approaches) is analogous to the walking robot flailing and oscillating its legs. Getting them right won&amp;rsquo;t directly lead to achieving success for students, but they&amp;rsquo;re foundational prerequisites to ultimately achieving that success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ESSA will give states the flexibility to develop accountability systems that acknowledge this better than NCLB-era accountability systems. States and the reform advocates holding them accountable would be wise to consider the objective paradox and grapple with the challenge of striking a balance between the competing desires for rapid improvement and allowing room for schools to develop solid fundamental practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fatal Conceit &amp; ESSA</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-12-01-fatal-conceit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-12-01-fatal-conceit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The curious task of economics is to demonstrate to men how little they really know about what they imagine they can design&amp;rdquo; - F.A. Hayek, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fatal_Conceit&#34;&gt;The Fatal Conceit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ink on the recently released Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA) is barely dry, but progressive ed reformers are already panning the proposed successor to the defunct No Child Left Behind Act (NCLB). &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/conorpwilliams&#34;&gt;Conor Williams&lt;/a&gt; argues that not only should Obama veto the NCLB rewrite, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.the74million.org/article/williams-why-progressives-should-fear-conservatives-should-hate-and-obama-should-veto-the-nclb-rewrite&#34;&gt;progressives should fear it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:cons&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:cons&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; His case for progressive opposition to ESSA boils down to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If this were a debate over clean water protections, voting rights protections, or most other policy issues, progressives would line up to yell about how states can’t be trusted to do the right thing without strong federal oversight.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This begs the question: what is &amp;ldquo;the right thing&amp;rdquo; for states to do? Is there even one &amp;ldquo;right thing&amp;rdquo; that can apply to all states? Reading Williams&amp;rsquo; argument, I kept hearing the Hayek quote above in my head.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:econ&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:econ&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not as confident that we know enough to design the accountability system he imagines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/michaelpetrilli&#34;&gt;Mike Petrilli&lt;/a&gt; wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;http://edexcellence.net/articles/lets-check-our-halos-at-the-door-education-reformers&#34;&gt;the ed reform movement&amp;rsquo;s need for more humility&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We know what works, we just need the political will to do it”: That’s the foundational creed of today’s reform movement. But what if the truth is closer to “We are just beginning to learn what works to help poor kids escape poverty, but we still don’t know how to do it at scale”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t agree more. As a movement, we&amp;rsquo;ve made some significant progress in figuring out &amp;ldquo;what works&amp;rdquo;, but what we have learned is dwarfed by what we need to know in order to provide all students with a quality education. This means that we not only need to invest more in research (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aei.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Greene.pdf&#34;&gt;Jay Greene&amp;rsquo;s writing&lt;/a&gt; for more on that), but we should also encourage and evaluate new approaches. ESSA would give states a great opportunity to expand our understanding of &amp;ldquo;what works&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, it looks as if ESSA is likely to pass and that most of the education policy action will (rightfully) be at the state level. Instead of giving in to the &amp;ldquo;fatal conceit&amp;rdquo; Hayek describes, I hope that both progressive and conservative reformers embrace the opportunity to adopt accountability systems that will challenge and improve the status quo in ways that acknowledge the current limits of our policy tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:cons&#34;&gt;Williams also argues that conservatives should oppose ESSA because it replaces relatively simple and clear federal accountability measures with more latitude for states to design their own systems. For conservatives, that is a feature, not a bug, for conservatives.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:cons&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:econ&#34;&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re at all interested in Hayek, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ve seen one of my favorite YouTube videos, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/d0nERTFo-Sk&#34;&gt;Keynes v. Hayek rap battle&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:econ&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How would great teachers spend a time bonus?</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-09-24-how-would-great-teachers-spend-a-time-bonus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 11:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-09-24-how-would-great-teachers-spend-a-time-bonus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This entire series of conversations with &lt;a href=&#34;fishman&#34;&gt;Fishman Prize&lt;/a&gt; winners is worth reading, but this passage stood out to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In so many ways, these hierarchies we have put teachers at the bottom. But that almost entitles everyone who is above us, so to speak, to put tasks on our plate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It perfectly captures my feelings after reading &lt;a href=&#34;allureoforder&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Allure of Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;teamofteams&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team of Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: our highly bureaucratized school system is limiting the potential of our students &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; our educators. When we treat educators as implementers of top-down policies, we fail to benefit from their ground-level insights, making our education system too rigid to respond to the dynamic needs of students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s time to consider &lt;a href=&#34;bt3&#34;&gt;a new approach&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Obama Education Legacy</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-09-23-the-real-obama-education-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 08:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-09-23-the-real-obama-education-legacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rick Hess summarizes the frustrations of center-right ed reformers with the Obama administration&amp;rsquo;s approach to education policy (myself included):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Although some of Obama’s education moves have been inopportune, his agenda has also included a number of notions with real promise. But his administration’s excessive faith in federal regulation, lack of time for the niceties of federalism, and contempt for critics helped undermine these ideas and support for reform more broadly. Perhaps above all, Obama’s education legacy shows that good ideas executed poorly can prove not to be such good ideas after all.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that my left-leaning ed reform friends take this criticism to heart. It also extends beyond the federal level: just like Presidents, governors and state superintendents don&amp;rsquo;t stay in office forever. If we&amp;rsquo;re going to succeed over the long term, thoughtful implementation matters just as much as having smart policy solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Taylorism, Part III</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-09-22-beyond-taylorism-pt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-09-22-beyond-taylorism-pt3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you&amp;rsquo;ve read articles, essays, and books that attempt to explain the root cause of the problems facing  the teaching profession.  In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Allure-Order-Expectations-Development/dp/0190231459&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Allure of Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Jal Mehta only needs one paragraph to break it down:
&amp;gt;&amp;ldquo;In the longer term, the success of the reformers in the Progressive Era resulted in a shift from one-room schoolhouses to urban school systems, in which schools were expected to follow the directives of a central manager in a district office. &lt;strong&gt;This effectively institutionalized teaching, not as a profession under the control of its frontline practitioners, but as an activity performed within a bureaucratically controlled hierarchy.&lt;/strong&gt; (emphasis added) Teachers and schools, at the bottom of an implementation chain, were responsible primarily for implementing the ideas of central office managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resonates with me. To be sure, there are examples of leaders and teachers that find a way to thrive in the system as it exists today, but they are by far the exception and not the rule. Teachers – particularly in urban school systems – feel constrained by the system within which they operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This actually reminds me of an moment from &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt; when McNulty reacts to a fellow officer issuing tickets for picayune offenses in order to comply with a directive from downtown to boost arrests:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baker, Let me let you in on a little secret, The patrolling officer on his beat is the one true dictatorship in America, we can lock a guy up on the humble, lock him up for real, or say fuck it and drink ourselves to death under the expressway and our side partners will cover us, No one - I mean no one - tells us how to waste our shift!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0763094/quotes?ref_=tt_ql_3&#34;&gt;James McNulty, &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To some degree, teachers in many school systems share this mindset. After years and years of reform after reform, many educators (rightfully, I might add) react to new directives from district leadership by thinking &amp;ldquo;this too shall pass.&amp;rdquo; The one time most teachers feel their agency is most powerful is when the classroom door closes and their implementation of district/state/federal policies is unsupervised.  This is not to say that most teachers shirk these responsibilities, merely that it is when they have the most power to control what they do and how they do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real issue raised by this scene in &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt; and what we see in many school systems today is that the on-the-ground knowledge of those implementing policy don&amp;rsquo;t have any effective avenues to influence a change in policy if something isn&amp;rsquo;t working. Treating teachers as implementers without a voice in crafting or evolving policy limits the responsiveness and efficacy of education policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as this bureaucratic structure constrains educators, attempting to fundamentally transform this system is extraordinarily difficult, with educators often playing a prominent role in resisting such change. Neerav Kingsland thinks this is due to the &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://relinquishment.org/2015/06/30/the-allure-of-order-book-review-part-i/&#34;&gt; Allure of Safety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;ldquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;educators seem unable to let go of the institutions and values that protect but ultimately limit them (thousand page collective bargaining agreements and district bureaucracies).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neerav also &lt;a href=&#34;http://relinquishment.org/2015/07/06/four-ways-to-unwind-the-allure-of-order/&#34;&gt;looked at how we might move beyond this arrangement&lt;/a&gt;, but only one of the four strategies he presents would keep public schools under the control of local school boards. He calls this strategy the &amp;ldquo;Fight for Finland&amp;rdquo; – it would involve keeping the current governance structure and focusing efforts on improving the quality of teacher recruitment/development in exchange for loosening accountability. I agree with his assessment that this approach would take decades and and may not even be likely to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other strategies he proposes involve relinquishment of public schools to non-profit and potentially some  for-profit operators. While I share his optimism with regards to the potential of these strategies to succeed in helping provide better options for students and families, I&amp;rsquo;m growing more skeptical of the political and social feasibility of these approaches. Americans generally like their schools run by their school board, not their state government, and especially not the federal government. There isn&amp;rsquo;t much evidence to suggest that communities are ready to dissolve the power of their school board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is there a way to maintain local governance of schools without accepting the deeply flawed status quo of a bureaucratized teaching profession? I think so, but it would require adopting the following &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Team-Teams-Rules-Engagement-Complex/dp/1591847486&#34;&gt;practices from Gen. Stanley McChrystal&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;Team of Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;District/state administrators moving towards an &amp;ldquo;eyes on – hands off&amp;rdquo; approach: Central offices and state departments of education would need to hand off a significant amount of policy authority to principals. McChrystal&amp;rsquo;s metaphor: act more like gardeners instead of a chess master. Instead of trying to plot every move, seek to empower others with the opportunities, tools, and relationships they need to succeed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More trust and freedom granted to teachers: In addition to providing principals with more power, even more freedom should be granted to educators to make decisions and develop new methods to educate students and collaborate with their peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McChrystal doesn&amp;rsquo;t write much about accountability within a &amp;ldquo;team of teams&amp;rdquo; environment, but I&amp;rsquo;d bet that he&amp;rsquo;d want to hold teams accountable for outcomes, not processes. To that end, I&amp;rsquo;d prefer that schools be required to report student outcomes on a variety of metrics (including standardized test results for &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; students) and that families were empowered to vote with their feet and move their children to a different school if they aren&amp;rsquo;t satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sounds awfully close to the system envisioned in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crpe.org/publications/democratic-constitution-public-education&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Democratic Constitution for Public Education&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;d prefer to maintain school boards instead of developing the &amp;ldquo;Civic Education Council&amp;rdquo; that Hill &amp;amp; Jochim describe. I would maintain a governance role for local school boards and an administrative role for the a central district office, but in a very different capacity. School boards would hire superintendents and audit/approve district and school budgets. Superintendents and central office staff within a district would focus on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collecting and sharing data (academic, financial, etc.) from schools transparently to help all staff understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening around the district at any given time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing principals with the support they need to hire and develop staff,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinating logistics (IT, food service, physical plant, etc.) and specialized services for students with IEP&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All other aspects of running a school – including hiring staff and educational operations – would be the responsibility of principals and the teachers in each school building. This would involve a complete re-thinking of collective bargaining in non right-to-work states, but it&amp;rsquo;s a compelling arrangement for all parties involved:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;School boards would focus on high-level governance and fiscal stewardship instead of academic policy – a much more appropriate role for elected community members that often lack a background in education.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;District staff would focus on supporting the educational process in schools more from a logistical than an academic perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;School staff would focus on what they do best: educating children.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be a significant shift in governance, but it would maintain important oversight by a locally-elected board. More importantly, it would free educators to operate as true professionals instead of implementers within a bureaucratic machine. I believe that compared to the alternatives, this system has the best chance of scaling to many communities while also creating the best conditions possible to allow educators to thrive and serve students well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Taylorism, Part II</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-08-01-beyond-taylorism-pt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-08-01-beyond-taylorism-pt2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we realized __________, we did what most large organizations do when they find themselves falling behind the competition: we worked harder. We deployed more resources, we put more people to work, and we strove to create ever-greater efficiency within the existing operating model. Like obnoxious tourists trying to make themselves understood in a foreign country by continuing to speak their native tongue louder and louder we were raising the volume to no good end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill in the blank with &amp;ldquo;our education system wasn&amp;rsquo;t preparing students for the demands of a more competitive economy&amp;rdquo;, and the rest of the paragraph is a pretty apt description of how policymakers at all levels of government have approached education reform since the release of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Nation_at_Risk&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Nation at Risk&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The passage is actually from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Team-Teams-Rules-Engagement-Complex/dp/1591847486/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team of Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, describing how the Joint Special Operations Task Force&amp;rsquo;s initial reaction to the nimble, decentralized enemy they encountered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for Gen. McChrystal to understand that achieving victory would require much more than either adding more resources or operating with more efficiency — it would require a complete shift in how his organization operated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jal Mehta&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Allure-Order-Expectations-Schooling-Development/dp/0190231459/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Allure of Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; shows how the last few decades of education reform (for the most part) followed the default approach described in the quote above. Inflation-adjusted spending on schools and the number of employees staffing them &lt;a href=&#34;http://dailysignal.com/2014/05/18/education-spending-test-scores-arent-whos-blame/&#34;&gt;have both skyrocketed&lt;/a&gt; relative to the modest growth in the number of students they serve, but we&amp;rsquo;ve only seen marginal improvements in student outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to the Task Force in 2004, our schools need to change &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; they operate in order to meet the complex challenges they face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most public school systems are set up as a reductionist hierarchy: teachers report to an assistant principal, assistant principals report to the principal, and principals report to a superintendent. Administrators devise how schedules and resources should be allocated. Teachers specialize in their roles and are expected to carry out the designs of those further up the chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would make sense if educating children was an easily repeatable and complicated process, like assembling an automobile, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. Again, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Team-Teams-Rules-Engagement-Complex/dp/1591847486/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team of Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; illustrates the difference between the complicated and the complex:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The workings of a complicated device like an internal combustion engine might be confusing, but they ultimately &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be broken down into a series of neat and tidy deterministic relationships; by the end, you will be able to predict with relative certainty what will happen when one part of the device is activated or altered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complexity, on the other hand, occurs when the number of &lt;em&gt;interactions&lt;/em&gt; between components increases dramatically — the interdependencies that allow viruses and bank runs to spread; this is where things quickly become unpredictable. &amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d argue that running a successful school is more like the latter description than the former. Students in great schools aren&amp;rsquo;t treated like cogs moving along an assembly line — they&amp;rsquo;re a part of several networks of relationships with peers, teachers, coaches, administrators, guidance counselors, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, in many public schools, teachers and administrators operate in a series of silos. This may make it easier for the science department to get better at running lab sessions, but it also makes it more difficult for staff across departments to collaborate and adapt in a fluid manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing the shortcomings of the Task Force&amp;rsquo;s structure, Gen. McChrystal decided to act:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We had to tear down familiar organizational structures and rebuild them along completely different lines, swapping our sturdy architecture for organic fluidity, because it was the only way to confront a rising tide of complex threats. Specifically, we restructured our force from the ground up on the principles of extremely transparent information sharing (what we now call &amp;ldquo;shared consciousness&amp;rdquo; and decentralized decision-making authority (&amp;ldquo;empowered execution&amp;rdquo;). We dissolved the barriers — the walls of our silos and the floors of our hierarchies — that once made us efficient&amp;hellip; We abandoned many of the precepts that had helped establish our efficacy in the twentieth century, because the twenty-first century is a different game with different rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mehta&amp;rsquo;s recognizes in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Allure-Order-Expectations-Schooling-Development/dp/0190231459/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Allure of Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  that &amp;ldquo;we need to design a new type of system, indeed to remake the sector as a whole.&amp;rdquo; He would prefer that a redesign focus on strengthening the professional practice and expertise of teachers, but Gen. McChrystal&amp;rsquo;s experience suggests that we may want to consider a different course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would it looks like for our schools to eschew their silos and hierarchies and become transparent, decentralized organizations? Even if we could imagine what this would look like, would it even be possible to make that transition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Taylorism, Part I</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-07-31-beyond-taylorism-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-07-31-beyond-taylorism-pt1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three books on three seemingly different topics changed how I think about public policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My reading list this month came together serendipitously. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arthurbrooks/status/616684322968465410&#34;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; led me to buy &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Conservative-Heart-Happier-Prosperous/dp/0062319752&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Conservative Heart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, I ordered &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Team-Teams-Rules-Engagement-Complex/dp/1591847486/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team of Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after listening to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://fourhourworkweek.com/2015/07/10/general-stanley-mcchrystal-on-anti-war-americans-pushing-your-limits-and-the-three-military-tests-you-should-take/&#34;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, and purchased &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Allure-Order-Expectations-Schooling-Development/dp/0190231459/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Allure of Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; after reading Neerav Kingsland&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://relinquishment.org/2015/06/30/the-allure-of-order-book-review-part-i/&#34;&gt;blogs&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://relinquishment.org/2015/07/02/can-we-unwind-the-allure-of-order-and-safety/&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://relinquishment.org/2015/07/06/four-ways-to-unwind-the-allure-of-order/&#34;&gt;it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a first glance, these books don&amp;rsquo;t look like they&amp;rsquo;d fit together. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Conservative-Heart-Happier-Prosperous/dp/0062319752&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Conservative Heart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is about communicating a conservative anti-poverty agenda. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Team-Teams-Rules-Engagement-Complex/dp/1591847486/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team of Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is about the lessons Gen. Stanley McChrystal learned while combating the insurgency in Iraq. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Allure-Order-Expectations-Schooling-Development/dp/0190231459/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Allure of Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; recounts a century of education reforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three books, with their own perspectives, share an important insight: &lt;strong&gt;complicated problems are different than complex problems, and they require very different approaches.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between a problem that is complicated and one that is complex? Arthur Brooks breaks it down in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Conservative-Heart-Happier-Prosperous/dp/0062319752&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Conservative Heart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Complicated problems are extremely difficult to understand, but they can be resolved with sufficient money and brainpower. And once you find the solution, the problem is permanently solved. You can replicate the solution over and over with a high degree of success. Designing a jet engine is a complicated problem. Figuring out how to build the first jet engine took sophisticated tools, computing ability, and expert engineers. But once engineers figured out how to do it—and designed a jet engine that worked—they could replicate the process and make jet engines routinely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complex problems are very different. They initially seem simpler to understand but can actually never be “solved” once and for all. One example is a football game. You know exactly what success looks like—it’s when your team wins. (In my case, it’s when the Seattle Seahawks win.) But there are so many trillions of combinations of things that can happen on the playing field, so many variables and ambiguities, that even the best data and strategies are dwarfed by the uncertainty that remains.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the turn of the century, businesses were grappling with complicated problems. Frederick Taylor is largely responsible for helping manufacturers treat organizational management like an engineering problem. Best practices were standardized across organizations while managers planned out the most effective ways for workers to carry out discrete tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_management&#34;&gt;Taylorism&lt;/a&gt;, the scientific approach to management spread far beyond the factory floor. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Team-Teams-Rules-Engagement-Complex/dp/1591847486/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team of Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; describes how Taylorist principles have guided the complicated operations of militaries for centuries. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Allure-Order-Expectations-Schooling-Development/dp/0190231459/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Allure of Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, we learn how Taylor influenced several waves of reform that focused on measuring results to drive greater efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s just one problem: our problems (particularly in education) are increasingly complex. And Taylorism is lousy when it comes to addressing complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, we have a framework that can help us move beyond Taylorism. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Team-Teams-Rules-Engagement-Complex/dp/1591847486/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team of Teams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; illustrates how the Joint Special Operations Task Force was able to transform how they operated in order to defeat a dynamic and decentralized enemy. More importantly, it outlines how leaders can move beyond running an efficiency-focused organization to leading one that can adapt to meet the needs of complex problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll dive in to the details of how this approach could help us address the problems raised in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Allure-Order-Expectations-Schooling-Development/dp/0190231459/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Allure of Order&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. At it&amp;rsquo;s heart, it&amp;rsquo;s about replacing a top-down, meddling mindset with one of my favorite McChrystal phrases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Eyes on — hands off&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deal on charters in detail</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-06-03-budget-deal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-06-03-budget-deal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://ctmirror.org/2015/06/01/deal-on-charter-school-conflict-more-funding-all-around/&#34;&gt;CT Mirror reports&lt;/a&gt; that Governor Malloy and Democratic legislators struck a budget deal that would allow two new charter schools to open as well as supporting the growth of existing charter schools.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On paper, this charter growth will cost the state $12.4 million in FY16, but it actually took an additional $23.5 million increase in FY16 ECS funding to make it happen. In other words, for every $1 in new funding to support growth in charter schools, legislators insisted that $2 went to support traditional public schools via ECS grants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alspur.com/tough-choices.html&#34;&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve noted&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s much easier for legislators to give districts more money instead of addressing the inconsistent distribution of current ECS funding. The question I&amp;rsquo;d like to address: how well does this budget distribute the new ECS funding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at towns&amp;rsquo; ECS funding gap compared to their increase in ECS funding by FY17, we see that there&amp;rsquo;s a trend, but it&amp;rsquo;s not very clear. Towns with larger gaps will see a larger boost in their ECS grants, but towns with similar gaps are getting very different increases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/finalBudgetDollarChange.png&#34; alt=&#34;gapchangedollar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we take a slightly different look at the changes, this time in percentages, the distribution of new ECS funding starts to make a little more sense:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/finalBudgetPctChange.png&#34; alt=&#34;gapchangepct&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chart shows a tighter correlation between the percentage of the fully-funded ECS grant towns currently receive and the percentage increase in their ECS grant by FY17. Towns that currently get the smallest percentage of their ECS grant target amount will receive the largest percentage increases in funding, while towns getting a higher percentage will see a smaller increase in funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By FY17, the ECS grant will be 77.9% funded, but 47 towns with more than 78% of their target ECS grant will see an increase in funding. This comes at the expense of towns that are still significantly under-funded compared to their ECS target. For example, Milford won&amp;rsquo;t see their ECS grant increase by a single penny, even though they get less than 40% of their target ECS grant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To put it in perspective, this is what the distribution of ECS grant &amp;ldquo;percent funded&amp;rdquo; will look like by FY17 (the first chart has a normal x-axis, while the second uses a logarithmic scale to better illustrate the left side of the distribution):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/finalBudgetFY17fundedPct.png&#34; alt=&#34;pctdistribution&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/finalBudgetFY17fundedPctLog.png&#34; alt=&#34;pctdistribtuionlog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer my original question, how well is this new ECS funding being spent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new funding will do some good for under-funded districts, but the following problems persist:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over-funded towns with low levels of poverty will continue to get more than their fair share in ECS grants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ECS formula still doesn&amp;rsquo;t fully account for the impact of concentrated poverty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choice programs, including charters, magnets, and vo-tech schools, are still funded via separate line items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much more work remains to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;According to another &lt;a href=&#34;http://ctmirror.org/2015/06/03/house-debate-begins-on-fiercely-contested-state-budget-deal/&#34;&gt;CT Mirror article&lt;/a&gt;, the additional funding will allow current charter schools to add approximately 700 students across the state. The new charters slated to open this fall in Stamford and Bridgeport would serve 168 and 250 students, respectively, in their first year of operation.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Choices</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-05-15-hardchoices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-05-15-hardchoices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are few people in Connecticut defending the current system of distributing Education Cost Sharing (ECS) grants. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s a formula that is supposed to guide annual appropriations, but there are two big problems. To start, the legislature hasn&amp;rsquo;t ever appropriated the level of funding the formula calls for. Given the economic tumult of the past decade and Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s somewhat anemic growth rate, it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to understand why this is the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Less understandable is how the legislature chose to allocate ECS funding. According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctvoices.org/sites/default/files/040215_approps_sb816_ecsmin50pct.pdf&#34;&gt;testimony submitted by Connecticut Voices for Children&lt;/a&gt;, the line item for ECS grants is about 77% of what it ought to be if it were fully funded. As I&amp;rsquo;ve noted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://alspur.com/a-thought-experiment.html&#34;&gt;a previous post&lt;/a&gt;, some towns get much less than what they should expect at this funding level and some get more. A lot more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/ecsFRPL.png&#34; alt=&#34;ecsfrpl&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chart above illustrates how close each town is to their targeted grant at a 77% funding level compared to the town&amp;rsquo;s level of student poverty&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty clear that there are many towns with low levels of poverty getting much more than they should be getting in ECS funding. Here&amp;rsquo;s the same chart with a logarithmic scale on the y-axis to make it easier to see which towns we&amp;rsquo;re talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/ecsFRPLlog.png&#34; alt=&#34;ecsfrpllog&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at this problem in real dollars shows a slightly different picture. A few towns (West Hartford, Danbury, Milford) are underfunded by millions and millions of dollars, while the big urban centers (Hartford, Bridgeport, New Haven) are getting at least $10 million more than they are supposed to receive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/ecsFRPLdollar.png&#34; alt=&#34;ecsfrpldollar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not too worried about the big cities getting relatively more funding at this point. Our state&amp;rsquo;s education funding formula should gives more weight than it currently does to students with additional learning needs and to towns with high concentrations of poverty. These cities have both, so I think this divergence from their adjusted ECS grant is justifiable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s much more difficult to come up with a good reason for overfunding districts with low levels of poverty. In effect, our state is providing extra subsidies to school systems in some of the most affluent communities in the state at a time when many school systems are struggling with their towns to meet the needs of their students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###What did the Appropriations Committee do to address this problem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Connecticut General Assembly&amp;rsquo;s Appropriations Committee attempted to address this issue in their version of the Governor&amp;rsquo;s budget bill, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cga.ct.gov/asp/cgabillstatus/cgabillstatus.asp?selBillType=Bill&amp;amp;bill_num=HB06824&amp;amp;which_year=2015&#34;&gt;H.B. 6824&lt;/a&gt;. While the Governor&amp;rsquo;s initial budget would flat-fund ECS grants for FY16 and FY17, the Appropriations budget would direct an additional $3.7 million in FY16 and $10.6 million in FY17 to some of the most underfunded towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, all other towns were held harmless, meaning that overfunded towns will continue to enjoy their ECS windfall at the expense of districts with greater financial needs. An updated version of the chart we started with doesn&amp;rsquo;t show a very different picture by FY17.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/appropsFRPL.png&#34; alt=&#34;appropsfy17&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Making hard choices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would happen if our legislators decided to end the overfunding of districts with lower levels of poverty? Would we be able to end some of the most egregious examples of under-funding in the current system of ECS grants?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we would need to decide which overfunded towns should lose their windfall. As noted earlier, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s wrong to overfund the big cities given the challenges they face. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll pick a limit of 25% Free/Reduced Price Lunch (FRPL) resident students to decide which towns should lose their ECS windfall. More than a third of Connecticut students qualify for FRPL, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s a fair cutoff to determine &amp;ldquo;lower poverty&amp;rdquo; towns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how many towns are overfunded and have fewer than 25% of their resident students in poverty? Ten? Twenty? Nope - the answer is 88. In other words, &lt;strong&gt;more than half of Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s 169 towns are lower-poverty towns getting more ECS funding than they ought to - about $59 million extra each year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That $59 million in overfunding to towns like Greenwich, Fairfield, and Guilford could go a long way towards bringing some of the most underfunded towns closer to their ECS target grants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say we wanted to bring every town up to at least 75% of their adjusted ECS grant&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This would allow the state to continue providing additional funding to the state&amp;rsquo;s highest-poverty districts while ensuring that no other districts were terribly far off of their adjusted ECS grant. This would cost just under $45 million, but it would still leave a few districts with ECS grants that are millions of dollars less than they should receive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/proposedECS.png&#34; alt=&#34;proposedfix&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/proposedECSdollar.png&#34; alt=&#34;proposedfixdollar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could use some of the $14 million left over&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to ensure that no town was more than $7 million away from their adjusted ECS grant. This would impact four towns (Danbury, Hamden, Stratford, and West Hartford) and cost about $8.3 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/proposedbonusECSdollars.png&#34; alt=&#34;proposedbonusfixdollar&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/proposedbonusECS.png&#34; alt=&#34;proposedbonusfix&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would leave $5.7 million that could be used in a variety of ways to help improve the quality of education in Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s most challenging areas instead of subsidizing towns with relatively low levels of student need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can understand why the Appropriations Committee chose to address towns with severely underfunded ECS grants. It&amp;rsquo;s always easier to give towns more grant money than it is to take it away. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to say that as long as ECS isn&amp;rsquo;t fully funded, that no town should see a cut in their ECS grant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those easy choices have consequences. The ECS formula, while flawed in many ways&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, does call for state aid to be distributed according to town wealth and student need. Ignoring the formula&amp;rsquo;s prescribed distribution has placed the state in the position of benefiting pretty affluent towns at the expense of the underfunded towns. In my example above, the towns identified as underfunded had nearly a quarter of their students qualifying for Free/Reduced Price Lunch (22.6%). In the overfunded, low poverty towns, that rate is only 10.9%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We elect leaders to make hard choices, but they&amp;rsquo;ve been taking the path of least resistance when it comes to ECS. There&amp;rsquo;s no way to get around it: the current distribution of ECS grants benefits our state&amp;rsquo;s wealthiest towns, forcing towns with more students in poverty to rely on local property taxes to make up the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year our legislators use the underfunding of ECS as an excuse to continue this practice is another year of additional burden to the students and taxpayers in these communities. It&amp;rsquo;s time to stop taking the easy road and do what&amp;rsquo;s right for our state&amp;rsquo;s towns and students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;All of the charts in this post use the size of a town&amp;rsquo;s name to represent the number of public school students that live there. That is to say, towns with more students will appear in a larger font than towns with few students.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;Town&amp;rsquo;s adjusted ECS grant = Town&amp;rsquo;s fully funded ECS grant * funding ratio. In the current budget, ECS is only allocated 77% of what the formula calls for, so a town&amp;rsquo;s adjusted ECS grant would equal 77% of their fully funded ECS grant.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;$59 million in overfunding - $45 million to bring every town up to at least 75% of their target grant = $14 million left over.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;More on this in future blog posts, but to keep it short, I think the ECS formula should weight more heavily for poverty, provide a weight for concentrated poverty, and include &lt;em&gt;all public schools&lt;/em&gt;. Yes, that means I think we should fund districts, magnets, and charters the same way.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More data please</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-05-12-more-data-please/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-05-12-more-data-please/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/robbiestells&#34;&gt;Rob Stellar&lt;/a&gt; wrote about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trendct.org/2015/04/29/only-1-in-4-hartford-high-school-grads-got-a-college-degree-within-six-years/&#34;&gt;low rate of college completion among Hartford Public School graduates on TrendCT&lt;/a&gt;. More importantly, he raised some important questions that may better explain what&amp;rsquo;s going on here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is preventing so many students who graduate high school from enrolling in college? Is it for financial reasons or lack of access to other resources/college prep programs? How well do Hartford high schools prepare students for college? For the students that do complete college, what type of degree did they obtain? What sets these students apart from their peers who do not finish college?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob doesn&amp;rsquo;t presume to know the answers to these questions - he suggests that more data is necessary to understand the complexities of this problem. A reasonable suggestion to help identify specific ways to help students in Hartford complete college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ctnewsjunkie.com/archives/entry/op-ed_no_more_data_ed_reformers_politicians_blind_to_data_we_already_have/&#34;&gt;CT News Junkie op-ed&lt;/a&gt; intended to counter Rob&amp;rsquo;s CT Trends piece by claiming that we need &amp;ldquo;no more data&amp;rdquo; on the subject, pointing to examples of how proficiency rates data and graduation standards may have been compromised in Hartford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the answer to incomplete or flawed data shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be no data - it needs to be better data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/03/opinion/sunday/how-not-to-drown-in-numbers.html&#34;&gt;recent article in the New York Times&lt;/a&gt; emphasizes the need for analysts to ask &amp;ldquo;What did I miss?&amp;rdquo; when evaluating easy-to-measure data. At the end of the article, the author notes an under-reported aspect of Bill James&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/book/moneyball-art-winning-unfair/id388217004?mt=11&#34;&gt;Moneyball&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; approach to baseball analytics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The numerical revolution he spearheaded was never about putting traditional experts out of business. It was about acknowledging our ignorance, then gathering and testing data, whatever its source.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; how we should be trying to understand how well our students, teachers, and schools are doing and what we can do to improve them. Let&amp;rsquo;s collect more data, test it, and use it to improve what adults are doing to improve student outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many schools are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/05/12/us/school-districts-embrace-business-model-of-data-collection.html&#34;&gt;already implementing a smart use of data to improve instructions and operations&lt;/a&gt;, but there&amp;rsquo;s still room to improve and include more sources of data. Student surveys, growth models, and more accessible data for researchers are just a few ways we could achieve a more robust educational dataset in Connecticut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we work towards building more robust datasets in the field of education, we also need to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re engaging in rigorous, transparent analysis. We also need to acknowledge the limits of what data can reveal to us. As noted statistician John Tukey observed:&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:tukey&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:tukey&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The data may not contain the answer. The combination of some data and an aching desire for an answer does not ensure that a reasonable answer can be extracted from a given body of data.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s collect more educational data and apply it appropriately - it&amp;rsquo;s the best way to answer how we can improve the way our public schools serve students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:tukey&#34;&gt;Quote is from Jeff Leek&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://leanpub.com/datastyle&#34;&gt;The Elements of Data Analytic Style&lt;/a&gt; - I highly recommend this e-book to any data analyst!
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:tukey&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data analysis on the go</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-03-22-data-analysis-on-the-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 17:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-03-22-data-analysis-on-the-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcompany.com/3042357/tableau-elastic-tinder-like-data-visualization&#34;&gt;Fast Company article&lt;/a&gt; describes Tableau&amp;rsquo;s latest app, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tableau.com/be-elastic&#34;&gt;Project Elastic&lt;/a&gt;, as a potential game-changer in mobile data analysis. The app would allow iPad users to move from an Excel file in Mail.app to an interactive chart with a few quick taps. Filters can be applied/removed with swipes, zoom levels are adjusted by pinch/spread gestures, and charts can be shared via email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a cleverly designed interface, but Elastic suffers from a critical problem: it assumes the user is accessing clean datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to &lt;a href=&#34;https://hbr.org/2012/10/data-scientist-the-sexiest-job-of-the-21st-century/&#34;&gt;popular belief&lt;/a&gt;, the real work of a data scientist isn&amp;rsquo;t sexy. A large chunk, if not a majority, of a data scientist&amp;rsquo;s time is typically spent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/08/18/technology/for-big-data-scientists-hurdle-to-insights-is-janitor-work.html?_r=1&#34;&gt;cleaning messy data&lt;/a&gt;. By encouraging users to jump straight from an email attachment to data exploration, Elastic can lead to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garbage_in,_garbage_out&#34;&gt;garbage-in, garbage-out&lt;/a&gt; analyses. This risk is only compounded by the targeting of the app to casual analysts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elastic is an admirable effort by Tableau to bring data analysis to the iPad, but it will encourage a flawed approach to data analysis. To paraphrase Jeff Leek, &lt;a href=&#34;http://simplystatistics.org/2015/03/17/data-science-done-well-looks-easy-and-that-is-a-big-problem-for-data-scientists/&#34;&gt;good data science may look easy, but so does bad data science&lt;/a&gt;. Elastic looks cool, but the appealing interface is a mask for an insufficiently rigorous approach to data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have serious doubts that quality data analysis can be performed from a tablet or mobile platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked about the potential for the iPad replacing the PC, &lt;a href=&#34;http://allthingsd.com/20100601/steve-jobs-session/&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs compared it to the replacement of trucks by cars&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When we were an agrarian nation, all cars were trucks, because that’s what you needed on the farm. But as vehicles started to be used in the urban centers, cars got more popular. Innovations like automatic transmission and power steering and things that you didn’t care about in a truck as much started to become paramount in cars. … PCs are going to be like trucks. They’re still going to be around, they’re still going to have a lot of value, but they’re going to be used by one out of X people. … I think that we’re embarked on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile computing is replacing PC&amp;rsquo;s for millions of people around the globe for tasks like email, photography, personal finance, and gaming, but there are still many jobs that ought not be done on a mobile device.  Attempting to move data analysis to the iPad makes about as much sense as trying to move a piano with a Prius - just because it&amp;rsquo;s possible, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it should be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: if someone emails you a spreadsheet, you should probably wait to get to a PC before attempting to dig in to the data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdated funding systems are limiting options for families in Connecticut.</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-02-09-outdated-funding-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-02-09-outdated-funding-systems/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-growth-of-school-choice-in-connecticut-1995-2015&#34;&gt;The Growth of School Choice in Connecticut, 1995-2015&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, families in Connecticut demanded more public school options for their children. Over the last two decades, state funding for magnet and charter schools grew significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/choicefunding/master/choicegrants.png&#34; alt=&#34;choiceGrants&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with this level of growth, thousands still end up unable to attend &lt;a href=&#34;http://articles.courant.com/2012-04-24/news/hc-school-lottery-0424-20120423_1_open-choice-open-three-new-magnet-choice-or-magnet-schools&#34;&gt;magnet schools&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sde.ct.gov/sde/lib/sde/pdf/equity/charter/report_on_the_operation_of_charter_schools.pdf&#34;&gt;charter schools&lt;/a&gt; due to limited capacity. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it seem reasonable that lawmakers would work to expand the number of public school options available to families?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Connecticut may be heading in the opposite direction. Some lawmakers are considering putting a moratorium on any further expansion of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cga.ct.gov/asp/cgabillstatus/cgabillstatus.asp?selBillType=Bill&amp;amp;bill_num=HB6414&amp;amp;which_year=2015&#34;&gt;magnet schools&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cga.ct.gov/asp/cgabillstatus/cgabillstatus.asp?selBillType=Bill&amp;amp;bill_num=HB6003&amp;amp;which_year=2015&#34;&gt;charter schools&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;choice-funding-in-connecticut-too-big-to-exist-as-line-items&#34;&gt;Choice funding in Connecticut: too big to exist as line-items?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the current system of funding school choice is expensive and downright Byzantine. A student can have their public education funded at least 10 different ways based on the type of school they attend.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; As the chart below indicates, this complicated system of funding is now equivalent to more than 15% of the main grant to school districts, the Education Cost Sharing grant (ECS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/choicefunding/master/choiceratio.png&#34; alt=&#34;choiceVsECS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freezing funding to schools of choice would be an easy way for legislators to avoid answering a simple question: why should more than 50,000 students have their public schools funded in different and inequitable methods?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-s-the-solution&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the solution?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a &lt;a href=&#34;http://ctmirror.org/2015/02/03/barnes-long-term-obligations-continue-to-squeeze-funding-for-poor-children/&#34;&gt;lean budget year&lt;/a&gt; with many tough short-term choices, but lawmakers need to think seriously about the future of our school finance system. I hope they keep these principles in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All public school students should have their public education funded by a combination of the state and by their town of residence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ratio of state/town funding should be determined by the relative wealth of the town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A student&amp;rsquo;s total level of funding should be determined by their learning needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The full funding for a student should follow them to the public school of their choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A funding system guided by these principles would benefit the state by focusing the school finance system on town wealth and student need instead of the label a public school carries. It would benefit towns by giving them a predictable level of costs - no matter what schools families choose, towns would contribute the same level of funding to their education. Most importantly, it would provide families with more choices for their children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;As noted in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://alspur.com/problem-with-ct-school-finance.html&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, this was detailed in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cga.ct.gov/ed/tfs%5C20110815_Education%20Cost%20Sharing%20Task%20Force%5C20120123/Education%20Cost%20Sharing%20Task%20Force%20Final%20Report%201-23-13.pdf&#34;&gt;ECS Task Force&amp;rsquo;s Final Report&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Thought Experiment</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-11-29-athoughtexperiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-11-29-athoughtexperiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What would happen if we actually followed the ECS formula?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two significant flaws in Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s current school funding formula, known as ECS (Education Cost Sharing):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does not reflect the actual needs of towns and students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It does not treat the thousands of students accessing school choice equitably.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on addressing those concerns in subsequent posts, but for a moment, let&amp;rsquo;s take ECS at face value and assume that the underpinnings of the formula are correct. If political processes had not brought Connecticut off of the ECS formula and we distributed current funding according to the formula, how might that change how dollars flow to towns?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, the ECS formula is somewhere around $650 million under-funded. That is to say, the legislature and governor have not found a way to follow the ECS formula as it was originally intended to operate. In lieu of actually following the formula, the money that flows from the state to towns to school districts has been manipulated by politicians each legislative session since the ECS formula was adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would happen if our elected representatives followed the distributive principles of the ECS formula, so that if the state could only contribute 80% of what the formula dictates, each town would receive 80% of what the ECS formula dictates they should receive?&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s figure it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fiscal year 2015 (FY15), ECS was about 75% funded, meaning that the state is paying about three quarters to the dollar of what the ECS formula actually dictates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SjbPi00k_ME&#34;&gt;shocked, shocked to learn&lt;/a&gt; that some towns are earning more than 75% of their ECS entitlement, while other earn less!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which towns are doing better/worse than they should be doing if current dollars were distributed based on the ECS formula?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/ecsDiff.png&#34; alt=&#34;absdiff&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which towns are benefiting from the current flow of ECS funding?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Town&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Adj. FY15 Over-funding&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Hartford*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$21,489,136&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Bridgeport*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$19,716,791&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;New Haven*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$18,926,723&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Naugatuck*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$4,757,282&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Meriden*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$4,352,828&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Groton&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$4,183,143&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Colchester&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$3,355,802&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Wolcott&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$3,339,954&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Norwich*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$3,217,643&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Ledyard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;+$2,969,683&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, the biggest beneficiaries of the current distribution of ECS dollars tend to be &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sde.ct.gov/sde/cwp/view.asp?a=2683&amp;amp;Q=334226&#34;&gt;Alliance Districts&lt;/a&gt;, a collection of 30 low-performing districts the Malloy administration placed a priority on supporting with additional funding (identified in the table with a *).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twelve towns are under-funded by at least $5 million according to the current ECS formula. West Hartford falls $20 million short. Danbury is $17 million short and Milford is more than $11 million under-funded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Town&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Adj. FY15 Under-funding&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;West Hartford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;- $20,029,204&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Danbury*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$17,489,274&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Milford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$11,180,390&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Norwalk*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$9,681,090&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Stratford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$8,680,338&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shelton&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$6,910,435&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Branford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$6,389,163&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Wethersfield&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$6,246,413&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Middletown*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$5,983,252&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Southbury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$5,557,434&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Hamden*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$5,269,591&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Stamford*&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;-$5,263,781&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s surprising to see five Alliance Districts on this list (again, identified with a *). The combined under-funding of these five districts (Danbury, Norwalk, Middletown, Hamden, and Stamford) is about $43 million, which is less than the $60 million over-funding of the big three cities (Bridgeport, Hartford, and New Haven).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at raw dollar differences is helpful, but Connecticut is a state with a few large towns and many medium and small towns. Let&amp;rsquo;s compare what towns receive now as a percentage of what they &lt;em&gt;ought to receive if we followed the ECS formula with current appropriations&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/alspur/ecstargets/master/figures/ecsPctDiff.png&#34; alt=&#34;pctDiffECS&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we&amp;rsquo;re able to see which towns are really benefitting from the current flow of ECS funding. There are 53 towns in Connecticut that receive about 32% more ECS funding than they ought to, given the current level of total ECS appropriations. This includes affluent towns like Greenwich, Darien, Fairfield, Madison, and Westport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which towns get the short end of the stick? Well, there are a dozen towns that receive less than &lt;em&gt;half&lt;/em&gt; what they ought to receive under the ECS formula:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Town&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;FY15 Funding as % of Adj. FY15 Funding&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Branford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;23.0%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Woodbury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;30.7%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Farmington&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;30.9%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Southbury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;32.1%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Orange&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;33.3%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Shelton&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;43.3%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;North Haven&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;44.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Trumbull&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;44.5%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Middlebury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;45.3%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Rocky Hill&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;45.8%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Westbrook&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;46.6%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;West Hartford&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;47.6%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place I call home, Branford, gets less than a quarter on the dollar of what we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be getting according to ECS with the current level of total funding distributed via the ECS grant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, &lt;em&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think the current ECS formula is correct&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but this thought experiment highlights the key challenges of reforming Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s school finance system if we kept total spending flat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &amp;ldquo;big three&amp;rdquo; Alliance Districts are doing much better than other Alliance Districts.&lt;/strong&gt; Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s big three urban cities (Bridgeport, Hartford, and New Haven) are doing very well under the current flow of ECS dollars, which is in stark contrast to other high-needs towns that are significantly under-funded (Danbury, Norwalk, Middletown, Hamden, and Stamford). In order for the big three to gain funding, there needs to be either an increase in overall funding or adjustments to the ECS formula to more heavily weight for poverty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are many (mostly affluent) towns that are receiving more than their fair share.&lt;/strong&gt; Many towns have already hit the ceiling on what they should be getting under a fully-funded ECS formula. Any funding reform that gives more weight to towns with high poverty would mean reduced funding for these towns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suburbs are getting a raw deal.&lt;/strong&gt; While there are some Alliance Districts that are relatively under-funded, the most disadvantaged towns are middle-class suburbs like Branford, Orange, and West Hartford. These are towns that should be pushing for immediate school finance reform, since they would stand to see the largest relative increase in funding, even with no new money added to the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of waiting for a court to compel the legislature to change ECS, leaders of middle-class towns and Alliance Districts should be working to develop an school finance &amp;ldquo;grand bargain&amp;rdquo; that could be implemented without significant additional revenue. This would likely need to include schools of choice (magnets, charters, etc.) along with some sort of regulatory relief to affluent towns that would stand to lose funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will any leaders take on this challenge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using a set of ECS funding targets from a handout at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cga.ct.gov/ed/CostSharing/taskforce.asp&#34;&gt;ECS Task Force&lt;/a&gt;, slightly edited to prevent any districts from receiving less ECS funding under a fully-funded ECS formula than they get right now. If/when more up-to-date figures become available, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to update this post accordingly. All code used to generate charts/data in this post is &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alspur/ecstargets&#34;&gt;available on my GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;I would prefer a formula that included more recent wealth/population data and more weight for towns with highly concentrated poverty.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the problem with school finance in Connecticut?</title>
      <link>/blog/2014-10-28-whatstheproblemwithctschoolfinance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014-10-28-whatstheproblemwithctschoolfinance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;School finance in Connecticut is broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The state&amp;rsquo;s main vehicle of support to public schools, the Education Cost Sharing (ECS) grant, sends $2 billion to local districts each year with the goal of equalizing the ability of communities to fund public education. Unfortunately, years of legislative tinkering with the ECS formula left Connecticut with &lt;a href=&#34;ecsformula&#34;&gt;a Byzantine approach to funding schools that takes more than 16 pages to explain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of this labyrinthine system, non-traditional public schools (including magnet, charter, vocational/technical, and agriscience schools) &lt;a href=&#34;ecstaskforce&#34;&gt;are funded under entirely separate mechanisms&lt;/a&gt;. In practice, this means that one student could have their education funded up to ten different ways&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach makes the bulk of Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s education aid unresponsive to the changing needs of communities and families across our state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of &lt;a href=&#34;tax&#34;&gt;the largest tax increase in state history&lt;/a&gt; and with &lt;a href=&#34;ctatrisk&#34;&gt;major financial challenges looming&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s not likely that our state will simply be able to address this problem with a significant cash infusion. &lt;strong&gt;We need to make difficult choices to improve how Connecticut allocates scarce resources for public education.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the state with &lt;a href=&#34;achievementgap&#34;&gt;the largest achievement gap in the nation&lt;/a&gt;, we need a better way to provide a high-quality public education to every child. I believe that a more equitable and responsive school finance system is an necessary mechanism to achieve that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It won&amp;rsquo;t be easy changing the status quo in &lt;a href=&#34;steadyhabits&#34;&gt;the land of steady habits&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to do my part to move the conversation in a productive direction. In this space, I plan on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detailing the challenges and competing priorities involved in school finance reform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposing policy approaches that take into account the educational challenges and fiscal realities facing our state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transparent analyses of school finance and demographic data. When possible, all code and data will be available on &lt;a href=&#34;github&#34;&gt;my GitHub page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s school finance system is broken. We need to fix it my making some tough policy choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;The ten ways of funding public school students in Connecticut include the ECS formula and the nine streams of choice funding found on p. 9  of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cga.ct.gov/ed/CostSharing/Documents/2013/ECS%20TASK%20FORCE%20Final%20Report%201-23-13.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;ECS Task Force&amp;rsquo;s Final Report&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>