<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ecs on @alspur</title>
    <link>/tags/ecs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ecs on @alspur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 09:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ecs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deal on charters in detail</title>
      <link>/deal-on-charters-in-detail/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/deal-on-charters-in-detail/</guid>
      <description>The CT Mirror reports that Governor Malloy and Democratic legislators struck a budget deal that would allow two new charter schools to open as well as supporting the growth of existing charter schools.1
On paper, this charter growth will cost the state $12.4 million in FY16, but it actually took an additional $23.5 million increase in FY16 ECS funding to make it happen. In other words, for every $1 in new funding to support growth in charter schools, legislators insisted that $2 went to support traditional public schools via ECS grants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Choices</title>
      <link>/hard-choices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hard-choices/</guid>
      <description>There are few people in Connecticut defending the current system of distributing Education Cost Sharing (ECS) grants. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s a formula that is supposed to guide annual appropriations, but there are two big problems. To start, the legislature hasn&amp;rsquo;t ever appropriated the level of funding the formula calls for. Given the economic tumult of the past decade and Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s somewhat anemic growth rate, it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to understand why this is the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Thought Experiment</title>
      <link>/a-thought-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/a-thought-experiment/</guid>
      <description>What would happen if we actually followed the ECS formula?
There are two significant flaws in Connecticut&amp;rsquo;s current school funding formula, known as ECS (Education Cost Sharing):
 It does not reflect the actual needs of towns and students. It does not treat the thousands of students accessing school choice equitably.  I plan on addressing those concerns in subsequent posts, but for a moment, let&amp;rsquo;s take ECS at face value and assume that the underpinnings of the formula are correct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the problem with school finance in Connecticut?</title>
      <link>/whats-the-problem-with-school-finance-in-connecticut/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/whats-the-problem-with-school-finance-in-connecticut/</guid>
      <description>School finance in Connecticut is broken.
The state&amp;rsquo;s main vehicle of support to public schools, the Education Cost Sharing (ECS) grant, sends $2 billion to local districts each year with the goal of equalizing the ability of communities to fund public education. Unfortunately, years of legislative tinkering with the ECS formula left Connecticut with a Byzantine approach to funding schools that takes more than 16 pages to explain.
On top of this labyrinthine system, non-traditional public schools (including magnet, charter, vocational/technical, and agriscience schools) are funded under entirely separate mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>